<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zeronet on Punkcoder Zeronet Site</title>
    <link>/tags/zeronet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zeronet on Punkcoder Zeronet Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 14:00:44 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/zeronet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is this thing on.</title>
      <link>/post/20190705-is-this-thing-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 14:00:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190705-is-this-thing-on/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve done any updating to the site so I thought that I would add a little extra life back into the workflow. Originally when I started using ZeroNet I was seeing that there were a lot of external connections to the outside world, especially with some of the sites that were replicating net sites. I am please to say that running and looking through all of the items that I was scanning today, I didn&amp;rsquo;t see a single connection that was traveling outside of zeronet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remeber Kids</title>
      <link>/post/20180313-remember-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 19:56:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180313-remember-kids/</guid>
      <description>When you are working with decentralized content or really any content at all make sure that you always, always, always make a back up copy of the private key. Because it will come back to haunt you in the end if you dont. Luckly I remembered to make a back up and keep it in a really safe place, hidden behind a password so secure that I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to think of what it is to save me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offline Zeronet</title>
      <link>/post/20170921-offline-zeronet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 08:56:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20170921-offline-zeronet/</guid>
      <description>So I ran a bit of an experiment, I was running zeronet is an offline mode and I noticed that there are some sites that are severly broken in a full offline state. For me it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of taking the train, but it&amp;rsquo;s important to note the opperation of a network of communications in the attempt of a full government shutdown, such as the one that was seen in Turkey in 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeronet Build Out With Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/20170919-zeronet-build-out-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 11:17:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20170919-zeronet-build-out-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>After going through and working with zeronet for a while, I thought I would share the process for getting a site up and running without the standard, clone site. Hugo, similar to Jekyll, is a fairly good option for doing this kinds of site since they create static sites.
I originally went out looking for solutions to create new sites I kept running into the &amp;ldquo;Get Started Quickly&amp;rdquo; process provided by the clone site button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Zeronet</title>
      <link>/post/20170918-hello-zeronet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 14:43:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20170918-hello-zeronet/</guid>
      <description>Hello Zeronet! I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in the development of a ZeroNet site for a while so this is my first attempt at getting something out into the decentralized web. I&amp;rsquo;ve been around for a bit, so here are some of the interesting and useful things that I have found floating around ZeroNet for others.
Get All Hubs</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>