<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>Dig Deeper</title>
    <id>https://digdeeper.neocities.org/</id>
    <link rel="self" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/atom.xml"></link>
	<updated>2019-06-10T18:30:00Z</updated>
	<icon>favicon.ico</icon>

<author>
  <name>Dig Deeper</name>
  <email>digdeeper@inventati.org</email>
  <uri>https://digdeeper.neocities.org</uri>
</author>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_CitizensFixRome</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Rome Citizens are Fixing their City where the Government has Failed</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-04-11-citizens_fixing_rome.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-04-11T06:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

Rome Citizens are Fixing their City where the Government has Failed

https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2019/apr/10/filling-a-gap-the-clandestine-gang-fixing-rome-illegally https://archive.fo/LJI1u

I wasn't supposed to post news anymore but since there's a really positive one, I can (and must!) do it with clear conscience:

City maintenance – or the lack of it – has long been a hot-button issue in Italy’s capital. There are an estimated 10,000 potholes in the city – a source of frustration for the many Romans who travel by scooter.

What is the government doing to fix those? Nothing whatsoever. Fortunately Rome has brave citizens who take matters into their own hands:

The seven clandestine pavement-fixers are part of a network of about 20 activists quietly doing the work that the city authorities have failed to do.

Gap have been busy over the past few months. In December they repaired the fountain, built in the 1940s, of the Principe di Piemonte primary school

They have to do that because the government apparently can't:

A few months ago, he recalls, city authorities came to fix it but only repaired the pipe, and left the structure as a whole unusable.

The government, of course, hates the fact that the citizens are doing anything like this...

To repair the fountain they entered the school without permission

...but nobody would have done it otherwise:

But in the case of the fountain nobody else was going to fix it for at least two years

Why does the government prohibit t citizen action that helps everyone? Because it robs them of power they crave. What would happen if people realized they could affect the world in real, physical ways, without begging a "representative" that doesn't really represent them? Maybe we could take off the CCTV cameras. Maybe kick out the landlords and stop paying rent. Maybe destroy the advertisements in public space. Maybe take over all business to take back what belongs to the workers in the first place (and fix all the ../ghost/capitalismcancer.html"current flaws of shopping that exist because people have no say). The possibilities are endless!

“It’s not like we’re a group of anarchists,” says Renato. “We’re just people living here in this neighbourhood where everyone knows each other, trying to make things better.”

Oh, but you are. That is exactly what anarchism is supposed to be about - bottom-up organization; controlling the territory you live in instead of relying on a ruler who's never even seen the place.

“I hope someone will follow our example,” says Nadir. “I would love to learn one day that Gap groups have formed in other cities.”

Me too. In recent years the news of t action has been scarce. And yet this is the kind of initiative which will bring a revolution - not posting on twitter, "liking" something on facebook, or voting for yet another useless politician. So we have to do our part and widely publicize every single one of them. For now, let's celebrate the people fixing the city of Rome!


</content>
</entry>


<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_ChinaPrison</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) How China Turned a City Into a Prison</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-04-07-china_prison.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-04-07T19:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

How China Turned a City Into a Prison

https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/04/04/world/asia/xinjiang-china-surveillance-prison.html"

Wasn't supposed to do news for a while, but since a friend graciously did a great writeup, I will jus to it here: https://rainheaven.neocities.org/news/2019.04.07-china-surveillance-prison.html"https://rainheaven.neocities.org/news/2019.04.07-china-surveillance-prison.html. No archive link since the news piece is in video format, so it would do nothing. All I will add is that a lot of this stuff I've predicted in ./technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery (but this time humans had their hand in it tly as well). More of this and worse is coming to your country soon.


</content>
</entry>


<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_GlobalCensorship</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Microsoft Calls On Tech Giants For More Censorship To Prevent People From Sharing, Viewing Violent Content</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-30-global_censorship.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-30T04:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

Microsoft Calls On Tech Giants For More Censorship To Prevent People From Sharing, Viewing Violent Content

https://www.oneangrygamer.net/2019/03/microsoft-calls-on-tech-giants-for-more-censorship-to-prevent-people-from-sharing-viewing-violent-content/81059/ https://archive.fo/94Jjg

Recall what I've said in ../ghost/mozilla.html"Mozilla - Devil Incarnate:

Okay, it's time for the final conclusion. Google, Microsoft, Apple, Facebook, Twitter, Amazon, and Mozilla are all different heads of the same hydra, looking to control the Internet and the world.

All the "competition" between the corporations is FAKE. Like left vs right, black vs white, woman vs man, Mozilla vs Google - all manufactured so that you're fighting useless wars while The Hydra uses its many heads to accomplish its aim of controlling the world.

And the proof appeared sooner than I had anticipated - all the big online corpos will now be collaborating to globally censor anything they don't like. From the news piece:

Microsoft also wants to pool resources with other tech giants, creating a globalized, one-tech-nation command center where they can initiate a protocol to remotely lockdown content deemed “violent” or “extreme” by the AI

[...] that the general public should not be allowed to spread, share, discuss, or access this information independent or separate from what the AI allows them to access

The implications of this are staggering and might be the most important news piece this month. The vast majority of online discussions happens on the above big corpo platforms - and now all of it will be completely controlled by the AI. It will decide what you can and can't post or see, and you will not even be aware that it's happening (if your rulers decide so). It is not enough for them to just remove content they deem offending anymore (or even arrest people) - you simply cannot be allowed to see it. Now how did this idea come about at all?

If Microsoft’s plan does go through and they manage to coalesce with Facebook, Twitter, and Google on stricter content sharing policies and digital social interactions, then they’ll basically be caring out exactly what the Christchurch shooter wanted.

So, it's the shooting again. Makes you wonder if it wasn't arranged to justify this exact initiative (so-called false flag attack)...And yes, the plan will absolutely go through. Do you really think they will pass up on this complete censorship opportunity? Brace yourself, for we're about to witness the full control of the Internet.

What can we do? Obviously, the first step is to immediately get away from all the big corpo platforms! To get your news, use independent websites like this one ^_^ (NaturalNews is another good one). As for discussion - find some smaller Internet forums, especially those with little or no censorship policy (best bet is https://8ch.net). But even something like reddit - though it has lots of its own issues - is way better than succumbing to big corpo AI auto-censorship. A better, though less active, reddit alternative is raddle.me (warning - leftist focus, white man hating and all that; but you can discuss stuff there that you can rarely elsewhere, such as shoplifting). Become an adventurer and find your own places to hang around!

Long term, however, we have to move to platforms that we ourselves control. XMPP group chats, mailing lists, IRC, whatever. Even longer term, as explained in ../ghost/botnet.html"Avoiding "The Botnet" - impossible? - we must take over the networks. Since the elites will not stop at this in their psychopathic mission to control humanity. Soon, ISPs will join in and start blocking VPN, Tor, encryption, "terrorist" (non big corpo) sites, torrents - while we will be left increasingly helpless. So let's use the time we have on the relatively-free Internet to create a plan of action.


</content>
</entry>


<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Car_Speed_Limits</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Road safety: UK set to adopt vehicle speed limiters</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-28-car_speed_limits.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-28T11:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

Road safety: UK set to adopt vehicle speed limiters

https://www.bbc.com/news/business-47715415 https://archive.fo/bOyzr

Just another assault on our freedom and a march towards complete ../ghost/technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery.

EU Commissioner Elzbieta Bienkowska said: "Every year, 25,000 people lose their lives on our roads. The vast majority of these accidents are caused by human error.

Well guess what - A recent Johns Hopkins study claims more than 250,000 people in the U.S. die every year from medical errors. Other reports claim the numbers to be as high as 440,000. Where are the "EU Commisioners" calling for the ban on doctors? The 250,000 figure is from the US, while the 25,000 is from the whole EU. Taking size into account, the medical deaths still score way higher than the road ones - so since it is not about our safety, then what?

Under the new rules, cars will also be fitted with compulsory data recorders, or "black boxes".

That. Simply, everything you do inside your car is supposed to be recorded, and safety is just an excuse. There's something else still:

 You can force people to slow down, you can watch what they're doing, you can help them with emergency braking - but you can't get rid of basic bad driving. Unless, of course, you have self-driving cars.

Last sentence is the key - this is just another step to get people used to having less control over their vehicles. And ultimately, it will end with a total lack of control over your self-driving car. Boiling frog strategy - the same one that ../ghost/mozilla.html"Mozilla has used to control their users' browsing.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Firefox_Lockbox</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Firefox Lockbox Now on Android, Keeping your Passwords Safe</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-27-firefox_lockbox.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-27T12:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

Firefox Lockbox Now on Android, Keeping your Passwords Safe

https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/03/26/firefox-lockbox-now-on-android-keeping-your-passwords-safe/ https://archive.fo/KV4aB

The newest of Mozilla's security / privacy initiatives just got released for Android - a nice time to take a deeper look at it:

If you’re like most Firefox users, you have dozens if not hundreds of stored logins in your browser.

A bad security practice - https://www.bbva.com/en/internet-browsers-store-passwords-safely/https://www.bbva.com/en/internet-browsers-store-passwords-safely/

When you use Firefox Accounts you get to take your logins on the web in Firefox Mobile.

An even worse one, since all the data is stored on Mozilla's servers. Anyway, what I really wanted to do here was to analyze if the Lockbox is as private as they claim. Fortunately, Mozilla has graciously provided us a simple document showing exactly what data is collected, so let's use it. From https://lockbox.firefox.com/privacy.html"https://lockbox.firefox.com/privacy.html:

Credential data. Your credentials are synced in encrypted form using Firefox Sync.

With unreliable, in-browser encryption, I might add.

Interaction data. Mozilla receives information about your interaction with Firefox Lockbox, including (1) frequency of editing, viewing, copying, and syncing credentials, (2) whether you are a new or existing Firefox Account user, (3) interactions with Firefox Lockbox menus and icons, (4) length of time the app is in background.

AKA tracking literally everything you do on the app. No different than the well-known trackers such as Google and Facebook which Mozilla proudly speaks against.

Technical data. We receive your device, operating system, version, and language preference. We also receive your IP address in connection with your usage of a Firefox Account.

Add to that all the data about your machine. Is there anything left to track? Sure is - from https://github.com/mozilla-lockbox/lockbox-android/blob/master/docs/metrics.md"https://github.com/mozilla-lockbox/lockbox-android/blob/master/docs/metrics.md, we learn that they track pretty much every move possible, including when you:

Tap a credential in the credential list [...] Copy a credential to the clipboard [...] Autofill a credential stored in Lockbox into another app [...] Sync their credentials from the Firefox desktop browser [...]

As well as general patterns from all the users combined. Nothing is left except the passwords themselves, then (but can we really trust their unreliable in-browser encryption?). As we can see, another one of Mozilla's so-called privacy initiatives fails the sniff test. And, of course, the title already contains the shady marketing Mozilla is famous for.

But let us go beyond shitty Mozillaware for now. Should we really be using "services" like these at all? Sure they are convenient, but at what cost? Convenience is one of the biggest diseases of the modern world - the lack of challenge / effort required stuns mental acuity IMO. Not that we should suffer unnecessarily - but is it really such a problem to actually remember all your passwords? You have a head for a reason and it's the only place out there that is truly secure (no one's going to crack your skull for the passwords ^_^). Often, the newfangled "convenient" solutions end up being worse over the long run than the old reliables. We can already see that with the "web frameworks" for example - no one can make a website tly in HTML / basic CSS anymore and we end up with a bloated, ugly mess which everyone now hates. This whole convenience issue requires a more thorough analysis though - subject for another article!

</content>
</entry>


<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Unavoidable_Ads</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) MoviePass founder wants to use facial recognition to score you free movies</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-25-face_recognition_payment.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-25T16:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>
MoviePass founder wants to use facial recognition to score you free movies

https://www.cnet.com/news/moviepass-founder-wants-to-use-facial-recognition-to-score-you-free-movies/ https://archive.fo/4eU5F

PreShow is developing an app to earn you free movie tickets -- to any film in any theater -- if you watch 15 to 20 minutes of high-end advertising.

Accept crap being dumped into your brain for the right to watch a movie (which often means more crap). But how are they going to accomplish this?

Forgoing a password, PreShow's app will only unlock with your phone's facial recognition technology. And while you're watching the ads to earn that free ticket, your phone's camera monitors your level of attention. Walk away or even obscure part of your face? The ad will pause after five seconds.

Watch out, we're entering a new era of unavoidable ads. Forget about stupid movies - soon the entire Internet could be in on this. Just like sites don't work without JavaScript these days, you will have sites not working without facial recognition technology enabled.

So long as the front-facing camera can recognize that your face is looking at the screen, the border stays green. Walk away, t your head away from the camera or even obscure part of your face, and the outline turns to red in the demo. After five seconds of red, the commercial automatically pauses.

No more walking away while the ad is playing.

The app [...] won't be sharing personally identifiable data to third parties. For its advertising partners, it will provide aggregated and anonymized data

AKA the excuse of all disgusting trackers, such as Mozilla.

Anyway, let's think about the deeper implications. We're slowly entering a world where you pay for stuff with your privacy and dignity. What else could this technology be used for? I can just imagine ensuring that children view state / business sponsored propaganda in schools, for example. The possibilities are endless, and all lead to ./technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery.


</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_GoFundMe_Censorship</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) GoFundMe bans anti-vaxxer funding campaigns to curb misinformation</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-25-gofundme_censorship.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-25T16:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
GoFundMe bans anti-vaxxer funding campaigns to curb misinformation

https://www.slashgear.com/gofundme-bans-anti-vaxxer-funding-campaigns-to-curb-misinformation-24570870/ https://archive.fo/1Y0fH

Let's first look at how GoFundMe advertises itself on their website:

Free fundraising for the people and causes you care about

Unless it's causes you don't agree with, huh? Now from the news piece:

Crowdfunding platform GoFundMe has banned campaigns that seek funds for spreading misinformation related to vaccines, the company has revealed

Misinformation is a code word for information we don't like and want to remove from existence. Mozilla knows a lot about this stuff...

An increasing number of tech companies have cracked down on anti-vaccination content, including Facebook and Pinterest, and now GoFundMe is among them.

Yes, there is a massive censorship campaign not only against anti-vaccine material, but many other alternative theories. Unfortunately, even regular people - which claim to hate censorship - suddenly switch sides when presented with information they don't like. For those, let me share this poem:


    First they came for the socialists, and I did not speak out—because I was not a socialist.

    Then they came for the trade unionists, and I did not speak out— because I was not a trade unionist.

    Then they came for the Jews, and I did not speak out—because I was not a Jew.

    Then they came for me—and there was no one left to speak for me.


What people don't understand is that this issue isn't about vaccination at all, or even censorship altogether. The real point is: big online corpos can pull the rug from under your feet, and there's nothing whatsoever you can do since they own the platforms. That is the thing we should fight first, since it is the root of the problem - see ./botnet.html"Avoiding "The Botnet" - impossible?


</content>
</entry>



<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Uber_Stealing_Drivers</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Uber used secret spyware to try to crush Australian start-up GoCatch</title>
<category term="capitalism"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-21-uber-stealing-drivers.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-21T08:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Uber used secret spyware to try to crush Australian start-up GoCatch

https://www.abc.net.au/news/2019-03-18/uber-used-secret-spyware-to-try-and-crush-australian-start-up/10901120 https://archive.fo/QmHTX

GoCatch was a major competitor to Uber when the US company launched in Australia in 2012. At the time, both companies were offering a new way to book taxis and hire cars using a smartphone app.

Two companies with competing products - just the free market at work.

A former senior Uber employee has told Four Corners that the idea behind the use of the Surfcam spyware was to starve GoCatch of drivers.

But one of them decided it will have none of it - there's space only for one of them!

Surfcam allowed Uber Australia to see in real time all of the competitor cars online and to scrape data such as the driver's name, car registration, and so on.

GoCatch would lose customers due to poaching of its drivers draining their supply. With fewer and fewer drivers, GoCatch would eventually fold," the former Uber employee said.

And so, they developed a program to steal the competing company's clients.

The damage that that has done to GoCatch and other businesses is significant and frankly it should have been stopped.

So the government should have intervened in the free market? Heresy.

Surfcam was part of an aggressive strategy Uber pursued under co-founder Travis Kalanick to establish itself globally amid fierce opposition from authorities and the taxi industry.

A company wanted to kill its opposition? Impossible.

Mr Campbell believes local authorities failed to protect Australian companies with the existing laws when Uber entered the country.

As is it supposed to happen under the free market, isn't it? The point is, the anarcho-capitalist utopia cannot exist! If companies are allowed to do whatever they want, they will use every dirty trick available to bury the competition. It's not the better product that wins under anarcho-capitalism (contrary to their claims), but the one that's better able to impose itself onto the competition - such as by aggressive / false advertising, https://www.ctvnews.ca/business/david-and-goliath-battle-prompted-predatory-pricing-probe-into-westjet-flair-ceo-1.4214887"predatory pricing, showrooming (Amazon’s new smartphone, called Fire (apparently meant in the sense of “shoot to kill”), is specifically designed to make showrooming fast and easy. Amazon has even offered $5 rebates to shoppers who scan items at stores, then buy them from the online brute.), https://www.businessinsider.com/details-from-news-corps-latest-ad-hacking-scandal-alleges-execs-used-al-capone-as-a-role-model-2012-12"hacking, or simply https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3241707"buying them out. I've even heard of companies literally hiring random people off the street to throw trash or make noise around a rival's place - and these are small, local ones - the anarcho-capitalist's dream...Anyway, back to Uber:

An Uber Australian spokeswoman said the company had conducted an audit of the use of Surfcam and it has been prohibited.

So you've killed the competition and now are withdrawing the dirty tactics (since you don't need them anymore). Hooray for the free market!


"We are on record consistently welcoming competition; we have robust policies and guidelines which define acceptable and ethical practices across our global operations for the use of non-confidential, publicly available and commercially available information in compliance with relevant Australian and international law."


Yawn. PR-talk of which even Mozilla would be proud.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Spying_Cars</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) The Spy Inside Your Car</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
<category term="capitalism"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-17-spyingcars.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-17T09:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
The Spy Inside Your Car

http://fortune.com/2019/01/24/the-spy-inside-your-car/ https://via.hypothes.is/http://fortune.com/2019/01/24/the-spy-inside-your-car/

An estimated 120 million cars will be equipped with voice-recognition systems next year, up from 40 million in 2018, according to IHS Markit. Currently, most in-car systems are smartphone-based, but Amazon and Google are also developing embedded devices that can work in cars without being tethered to a phone.

“I would imagine that within five years, the vast majority of new vehicles will have some form of voice recognition.”

So your car will have voice recognition. But what does it entail?

While it may be convenient for cars to know your shopping habits and favorite places, that information can also be used to create targeted audio or visual ads, sell subscription services, or tip off third-party businesses.

Targeted ads in your Internet, your TV, your phone, and now your car. But that's just the beginning:

 The most worrisome are incidents in which the devices accidentally record and send conversations to contacts in users’ phones, or inadvertently make large purchases.

Your private conversations are no more (thanks to an accident, of course). So we can expect something similar to the https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-23-alexa_police.html"home assistant situation I've wrote about before, where everything you say is sent to the police - and you can get penalized for it.

But even as governments and corporations begin to address security questions, it’s unclear who will control the data that is collected.

What is clear is it will not be you! The bigger issue, perhaps, is that we've given up control for convenience. What is the problem with remembering your own appointments, choosing your own shopping places instead of being "recommended" while you drive near them, or leaving your house in a proper state instead of relying on an "assistant" ? We've turned to technology to do stuff we've done tly just a while ago, losing our humanity. Who knows what kind of long term effects that's going to have? I mean children who use smartphones a lot end up https://www.kxnet.com/news/bismarck-news/study-smartphones-mess-with-your-kids-brains/1650758076"all kinds of fucked up https://via.hypothes.is/https://www.kxnet.com/news/bismarck-news/study-smartphones-mess-with-your-kids-brains/1650758076"(archive), and do you really think adults avoid the effects?

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Amazon_Book_Burning</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Amazon removes books promoting autism cures and vaccine misinformation</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
<category term="capitalism"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-14-amazon_book_burning.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-14T14:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Amazon removes books promoting autism cures and vaccine misinformation

https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/internet/amazon-removes-books-promoting-autism-cures-vaccine-misinformation-n982576 https://via.hypothes.is/https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/internet/amazon-removes-books-promoting-autism-cures-vaccine-misinformation-n982576

Amazon is removing from its online marketplace “autism cure” books that unscientifically claim children can be cured of autism with pseudoscientific methods such as ingesting and bathing in a potentially toxic form of bleach and taking medication meant to treat arsenic and lead poisoning.

How about letting the buyers decide if these are unscientific or potentially toxic?

At the time of its removal, “Fight Autism and Win” sold for $25 and had a 4.8 star rating and 54 customer reviews.

We're going to censor your ass, quality of the book be damned!

“During our review process, we found that the subject matter of your book is in violation of our content guidelines,” the screenshot posted by Cook stated. “As a result we cannot offer this book for sale.”

And no specific violation was cited. What this actually is is modern book burning. Whatever you think about the autism cures or anti-vaccination, you should be against this attack on buyer choice. Situations like these reveal who really cares about freedom and who just pretends to until someone says something he doesn't like. And unfortunately, most people seem to be the latter - even in communities you'd think would know better! Since many platforms such as YouTube, Twitter, Twitch etc. are doing the same thing, we could soon have a world where all the content you are allowed to see is carefully controlled by the elites.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Smart_TV_Ads</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Vizio wants next-generation smart TVs to target ads to households</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-14-smart_TV_ads.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-14T13:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Vizio wants next-generation smart TVs to target ads to households

https://www.reuters.com/article/us-vizio-advertising/vizio-wants-next-generation-smart-tvs-to-target-ads-to-households-idUSKBN1QT16V https://archive.fo/uC8nS

While Inscape, which specializes in smart TV data, will build the technology, it will be an open standard, meaning any TV manufacturer or connected-device company will be able to integrate the standard in their products.

The consortium of companies, dubbed Project OAR, or Open Addressable Ready, hopes to define the technical standards for TV programmers and platforms to deliver addressable advertising on smart TVs, which are WiFi-enabled TVs with apps for services like Netflix Inc and Hulu, by the end of this year, McAfee said.

So, a year from now every smart TV is supposed to have targeted advertising (I mean you don't think companies won't jump at the opportunity, do you?). The plan, it seems, is to have mind control in every house. This is like the Alexa assitant that worked with the police - there's no "safe space" anymore - they will get you everywhere. Unless you live alone, and can avoid those products - but the issue of visiting others (say, family that doesn't care about privacy) is still there.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Firefox_Send</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Introducing Firefox Send, Providing Free File Transfers while Keeping your Personal Information Private </title>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-14-firefox_send.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-14T07:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Introducing Firefox Send, Providing Free File Transfers while Keeping your Personal Information Private

https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/03/12/introducing-firefox-send-providing-free-file-transfers-while-keeping-your-personal-information-private/ https://archive.fo/nLMkD

Another "private" invention from the ../ghost/mozilla.html"evil Mozilla. Let's just lift the veil and get it over with:


We receive IP addresses of downloaders and uploaders as part of our standard server logs. These are retained for 90 days, and for that period, may be connected to activity of a file’s download URL. Although we develop our services in ways that minimize identification, you should know that it may be possible to correlate the IP address of a Send user to the IP address of other Mozilla services with accounts; and if there is a match, this could identify the account email address.

Logs IP for 90 days, connects that to the uploaded file - which means everything they collect is attached to your IP. Next: the interaction data they admit to storing:

This includes information such as number of people sending and receiving files, number of files uploaded and approximate file sizes, percentage of file downloaders who become uploaders, how people engage with the website (time spent, clicks, referrer information, site exit path, use of passwords).

Time spent, clicks, referrer information - very private indeed. Now the technical data:

This includes information such as operating system, browser, language preference, country, timestamps, duration for file transfer, reasons for errors, reasons for file expiration.

Timestamps, browser, system...it seems they get their hands on everything they can - except allegedly the file's actual contents. But http://127.0.0.1/digdeeper/ghost/email.html#Encryption"metadata can reveal a lot, so how does that really help? And Mozilla deceptively calls it Non-personal data - what a joke.

All in all, another ../ghost/fake_initiatives.html"fake initiative from Mozilla. What's the alternative? https://upload.disroot.org/Disroot to the rescue as usual! Also has one GB maximum file size with no account required and doesn't store IP or the other stuff.
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Robots_Replace_Bartenders</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) MGM Could Replace Many Employees with Robots</title>
<category term="AI"></category>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="capitalism"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-09-robot_replaces_employees.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-09T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
MGM Could Replace Many Employees with Robots

https://www.vegasslotsonline.com/news/2019/03/07/mgm-could-replace-many-employees-with-robots/ https://archive.fo/8BjKh

Among those who could be replaced are cashiers and bartenders. Automatic technology that can make drinks would replace the bartenders and monetary transactions could be done through standard payment technology.

There would also be mobile payment processors going around the floor with the wait staff, eliminating the need for cashiers. There is no indication as to how many such jobs would be replaced at the MGM properties.

Cashiers and bartenders - exactly as said in my https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/capitalism.html"Capitalism will die - but will it take us with it? article.

The Las Vegas Culinary Union (LVCU), which represents bartenders, kitchen staff, and wait staff, reached a five-year deal in June 2018 with the MGM.

The agreement guarantees that MGM will not implement any technology that would have a negative impact on employment. However, the news that the MGM is considering replacing some workers with robots could mean that the company is not willing to fulfill this agreement.

So the company promised they will not be replacing people with robots, and is now breaking that promise. Robot revolution can't be denied.

A McKinsey and Company report estimates that robots could take over as many as 800 million jobs globally by 2030. This is especially the case in advanced economies, such as in the United States.

Recall what I've said in my article - I think it will take no more than 10 years to see the huge effects of the robot revolution all over the world. Seems I've got it exactly right - over 10% of people in the whole world will be kicked out of their jobs by 2030, and be at the mercy of the governments. But wait, the capitalists have an answer as usual:

As a result, millions of people will have to learn new skill sets in order to adapt and find employment.

Not all industries will face the same struggles. Jobs involving social interaction, applying expertise, or managing people naturally will not be replaceable by robot technology.

The standard blaming of the victim - just get better skills! And of course those engineer and scientist jobs will appear out of thin air for all the teenagers to do. Forget about this - those people will be left to die. That's why capitalism has to be killed and we don't have much more time before the corpses line up the streets (as the report above proves).

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Shoplifting_Cameras</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Cameras Can Spot Shoplifters Even Before They Steal</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-06-cameras_shoplifting.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-06T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>

Cameras Can Spot Shoplifters Even Before They Steal

https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-03-04/the-ai-cameras-that-can-spot-shoplifters-even-before-they-steal https://via.hypothes.is/https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-03-04/the-ai-cameras-that-can-spot-shoplifters-even-before-they-steal

Recall what I've wrote in ./technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery:

Advanced cameras can do much more than just recording video and relying on the human's interpretation [...] They can also detect your behavior and mark it as potentially "suspicious" [...] But anything at all can be considered "suspicious". Let's look at some of the common things that I've seen being banned: selling stuff on the streets, feeding birds, wearing a mask, walking the dog (!), driving without seat belts, etc. Sometimes people get fined for these things, but they have to be found out first. The intelligent monitoring system removes this requirement, letting the psychopathic elites fine anyone for anything they imagine.

Somehow I missed shoplifting - should have expected that they're going to go after that first, since it strikes right at the heart of the capitalist system.

Like a scene out of the movie “Minority Report,” algorithms analyze security-camera footage and alert staff about potential thieves via a smartphone app. The goal is prevention; if the target is approached and asked if they need help, there’s a good chance the theft never happens.

As with every such AI application, we will end up with massive amounts of false positives - which hilariously means random people will get asked if they "need help" all the time. But that's not the important part here, so let's look further:

Vaak made headlines last year when it helped to nab a shoplifter at a convenience store in Yokohama. Vaak had set up its software in the shop as a test case, which picked up on previously undetected shoplifting activity. The perpetrator was arrested a few days later.

So there has already been a victim. Success for AI! No thief will get away anymore! Except, of course, all the capitalists...

“I thought then, ‘Ah, at last!’” said Vaak founder Ryo Tanaka, 30. “We took an important step closer to a society where crime can be prevented with AI.”

Yeah, starting with shoplifting, we can now expect them to go after all the "suspicious" behaviors I've described in ../ghost/technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery. Think about that the next time your dog shits on the grass...

Shoplifting cost the global retail industry about $34 billion in lost sales in 2017 — the biggest source of shrinkage, according to a report from Tyco Retail Solutions. While that amounts to approximately 2 percent of revenue, it can make a huge difference in an industry known for razor-thin margins.

Good. The retail industry consists mostly of deceptively selling people shit they don't need. Capitalism has made a world where your worth is determined by the shiny new things you've got, and the less money going towards that, the better.

The opportunity is huge. Retailers are projected to invest $200 billion in new technology this year, according to Gartner Inc., as they become more open to embracing technology to meet consumer needs

200 billion! Recall the quote above which says the capitalists only lost 34 billion through shoplifting. So they will pay five times more than that to spy on customers, which means they would be better off if they just left them alone! That's assuming the technology will actually prevent ALL shoplifting which of course is unrealistic. Most likely they will end up 10 or 20 times worse off. But if they are so eager to burn capitalism to the ground, so be it - I certainly don't mind.

The company began selling a market-ready version of its shoplifting-detection software this month, and is aiming to be in 100,000 stores across Japan in three years.

They're set in their ways though. You will be spied on and that's it!

The ability to detect and analyze unusual human behavior also has other applications. Vaak is developing a video-based self-checkout system, and wants to use the videos to collect information on how consumers interact with items in the store to help shops display products more effectively.

And you thought regular advertising was bad - now you will deal with what is pretty much mind control.

Beyond retail, Tanaka envisions using the video software in public spaces and train platforms to detect suspicious behavior or suicide jumpers.

Yeah, they admit to it - we're going to have to endure a full-on technological slavery system. And stop pretending you care about suicide, capitalists - since it's your system that mostly causes them in the first place!

To recap - for now, you will be AI-spied on in shops allegedly to prevent shoplifting (even though the real thieves are capitalists, and we're just taking back what's ours). Now, many shoplifters only do so because they're too poor to afford necessities - and by taking that option away from them, you're killing them. What causes poverty? Capitalism, of course - and it will get worse due to the robot revolution. Low-skilled jobs are mostly going away, as I've wrote in https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/capitalism.html"Capitalism will die - but will it take us with it? And yet, this murderous system is being praised even by the very people it harms - how insane.
</content>
</entry>


<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Tencent_Digital_Lock</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Tencent adds "digital lock" to certain games in China</title>
<category term="gaming"></category>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-03-04-tencent_gaming_lock.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-04T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Tencent adds "digital lock" to certain games in China

https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2019-03-01-tencent-adds-digital-lock-to-certain-games-in-china https://archive.fo/NxlRk

Tencent is using technology such as facial recognition and player ID checks to ascertain the ages and identities of those playing Honour of Kings and other titles in China.

Age checks have been a staple for very long time, but it's the first time I see it done through fucking facial recognition. Pure ../ghost/technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery. Of course, as with every invention like that, there will be many flaws - people with younger-looking faces will be penalized. We can expect much hilarity coming out of this, similar to what happened with Content ID that flagged bird songs as copyrighted.

In addition, it has already imposed limits on how long young players can play the game, and imposed rules for streaming its game content prohibiting things like violence, information about gambling or pornography, national politics, or other "damaging behavior."

So the government replaces the parent. I get it, it's in China - but that doesn't mean it's not coming to your country soon as well. Consider this a preparation for what the elites are about to do - instead of a reason to claim your country superior. In fact, YouTube, Twitch, etc. are already censoring streams just like Tencent does it. Also a reminder to not play shitty mobile games that are easily controlled.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Palemoon_uMatrix</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Pale Moon gets an uMatrix fork</title>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
<category term="positive"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-28-palemoon_ematrix.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-02-28T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Pale Moon gets an uMatrix fork

https://addons.palemoon.org/addon/ematrix/ (to the extension)

Let's have some positive news for a change. Up until now, only Chrome based and Firefox based browsers supported uMatrix. So you had to deal with big corpo bullshit if you wanted to use it, and since it's pretty much an ../ghost/addons.html"essential addon...But now Pale Moon also has it, and the Google / Mozilla duopoly is officially broken. Pale Moon is a fork of a very old FF version, but has diverged so far that it develops its own engine and so is independent of Mozilla. It also has many other advantages over Google's and Mozilla's browsers. I've got it somewhat wrong when I shat on it in my ./browsers.html"browser article, and I will be modifying it soon. Regardless, rejoice!
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_AI_Monk</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Meet the AI monk: Buddhist robot costing £700,000 is now delivering religious teachings at a 400-year-old temple in the Japanese city of Kyoto</title>
<category term="AI"></category>
<category term="society"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-27-robot_sermon.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-02-27T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Meet the AI monk: Buddhist robot costing £700,000 is now delivering religious teachings at a 400-year-old temple in the Japanese city of Kyoto

https://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-6742903/700-000-Robot-deliver-religious-teachings-400-year-old-temple-Japanese-city-Kyoto.html https://via.hypothes.is/https://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-6742903/700-000-Robot-deliver-religious-teachings-400-year-old-temple-Japanese-city-Kyoto.html

The conditioning of humans to bow down to their robot overlords continues! The transhumanist cult has tried for a really long time to get people to accept the idea of merging with the machine. That's why they didn't even bother putting skin on the android, so you can see all his electronic stuff sticking out. Anyway, let's look at some of the quotes:


The android, dubbed Kannon, is based on the traditional Buddhist deity of mercy and is designed to attract young people.

Managers at the ancient venue approached Professor Ishiguro in a bid to connect with Japan's youth.

So, the point is to use religion to indoctrinate young impressionable people with transhumanism. But let's also think about the deeper implications. The robot knows two languages and can conceivably know more (maybe even all the world's languages?). Recall the holograms from the video game Deus Ex Invisible War? One of them had a singer who you were able to talk to...and the hologram was put in many places in the world in order to collect information for the government. It's easy to imagine the same thing happening in the real world with these robots to spread propaganda, for example. And the novelty of it will surely claim some victims at first, while later it will simply be accepted as an everyday thing like regular advertisements. Mind-control and transhumanism...can you say two birds with one stone?
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_License_Plate_Reader</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Privacy advocate held at gunpoint after license plate reader database mistake, lawsuit alleges</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-26-license_reader.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-02-26T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Privacy advocate held at gunpoint after license plate reader database mistake, lawsuit alleges

https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/21/18234785/privacy-advocate-lawsuit-california-license-plate-reader https://archive.fo/BvP1h

Bay Area police pulled over a California privacy advocate and held him at gunpoint after a database error caused a a license plate reader to flag a car as stolen

Hofer alleges that an officer had a gun drawn and told him and his brother to exit the rental car, and that a deputy injured his brother by throwing him to the ground.

The suit alleges the officers then searched the car without consent

So, a person was threatened with a gun, got his car searched and brother injured - all because an automatic plate reader fucked up. Shows the folly of relying on technology to detect "crime". You can expect these types of incidents to increase massively after the intelligent camera system I've described in ../ghost/technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery becomes commonplace.
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Alexa_Police</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Alexa, call the police! Smart assistants should come with a 'moral AI' to decide whether to report their owners for breaking the law, experts say</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-23-alexa_police.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-02-23T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Alexa, call the police! Smart assistants should come with a 'moral AI' to decide whether to report their owners for breaking the law, experts say

https://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-6733417/Digital-assistants-discuss-moral-AI-report-illegal-immoral-activity.html"
 https://via.hypothes.is/https://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-6733417/Digital-assistants-discuss-moral-AI-report-illegal-immoral-activity.html

Smart assistants could soon come with a 'moral AI' to decide whether to report their owners for breaking the law. That's the suggestion of academics at who say that household gadgets like the Amazon Echo and Google Home should be enhanced with ethical smart software.

Devices would then have an internal 'discussion' about suspect behaviour, weighing up conflicting demands between the law and personal freedoms, before arriving at the 'best' course of action.

And of course, the personal freedoms will end up secondary - if they are considered at all!

'If we want to avoid Orwellian outcomes it's important that all stakeholders are identified and have a say, including when machines shouldn't be able to listen in. Right now only the manufacturer decides.'

But what if they don't want to avoid Orwellian outcomes? Then only the manufacturer will decide, as they admit the situation is now.

In ../ghost/technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery, I've wrote that the elites intend to use intelligent cameras to live-analyze everyone's movement in regards to "suspicion". Of course, this only works on the assumption that people will act "suspicious" outside. They could easily keep their illegal acts in the house, which would be safe from the prying eyes. That problem is beautifully solved with these so-called smart assistants, and the house becomes enemy territory like the rest of the world already is.


</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Google_Police</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) How did the police know you were near a crime scene? Google told them</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-19-police-google.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-02-19T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
How did the police know you were near a crime scene? Google told them

https://www.mprnews.org/story/2019/02/07/google-location-police-search-warrants https://via.hypothes.is/https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/15/twitter-t-messages/


Law enforcement responded to a 911 call last October from an Eden Prairie woman who had just been robbed in her home. Her husband, Oukham Oudavanh, 63, suffered a heart attack and died at the scene, and the suspects made off with $50,000 belonging to the couple's popular food markets, Shuang Hur in Minneapolis and St. Paul.

Police wanted Google to identify all mobile devices in the area of the crime scene over a 6-hour time window. They also wanted location data for every cellphone in dense, urban areas surrounding the food market businesses over a 33-hour window.

If a device's location, movement, or timing established probable cause, investigators could go back to court and get a second warrant ordering Google to reveal the name of the cellphone's owner.

When Google provides location data in response to one of these warrants, police "put that location data into the software and then map out a 'profile of life' of where they go, where they travel, and where they were the night of the crime," Bruley said.

It presented a tough probable cause analysis, and police were asking for a lot: the identity of the phone's owner, billing information, phone numbers, and two months' of their web browsing history and location data. Google was also put under a non-disclosure order, restricted from telling the user that this information would be divulged for at least six months.

Asked earlier this week whether that suggests Brooklyn Park police got a data dump on the wrong person, Bruley cautioned against assuming that, saying that investigations take time. On Thursday, Bruley said police have closed the investigation, because Google ultimately could not track the data point.

So, whenever a crime happens, the police can now get location data from everyone that was near the scene. If your profile of life fit their criteria for "suspicious" they will also get massive amounts of your personal data. This is regardless of whether you are innocent (as was the person who's data they got in this case) or not. And you will never know any of this is happening. This is similar to what I've predicted in ../ghost/technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery, but I was mostly thinking about the data from intelligent cameras, not cellphones. But that will come soon enough as well - they will use every advantage the technological slavery system provides them. Of course this will be marketed as a triumph in regards to safety, even though "crime" is arbitrary and can change anytime at the whim of the rulers of this world.


</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Twitter_Deletion</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Even years later, Twitter doesn’t delete your t messages</title>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-16-twitter_deletion.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-02-16T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Even years later, Twitter doesn’t delete your t messages

https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/15/twitter-t-messages/ https://via.hypothes.is/https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/15/twitter-t-messages/

Saini found years-old messages in a file from an archive of his data obtained through the website from accounts that were no longer on Twitter.

But, in our tests, we could recover t messages from years ago — including old messages that had since been lost to suspended or deleted accounts.

As if we needed more assurance - "deleting" something from social media does not mean it's actually removed. The smart thing to do is to assume that all the tech giants are keeping your data forever. Recall that, as I've wrote in ../ghost/technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery - you can get arrested for apparently innocent stuff you post on social media - so it's better to avoid them.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Robot_Baristas</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Are robots better baristas? Berkeley's Bbox café thinks so</title>
<category term="AI"></category>
<category term="capitalism"></category>
<category term="society"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-15-robot-baristas.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-02-15T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Are robots better baristas? Berkeley's Bbox café thinks so

https://www.berkeleyside.com/2019/02/15/are-robots-better-baristas-berkeleys-bbox-cafe-thinks-so https://archive.fo/LnDhn

The replacement of people by robots continues (as I've ../ghost/capitalism.html"written before). The whole article goes to great lengths to deride us:

That’s largely because Bbox has eliminated one of the most expensive elements of operating a business: labor.

We're expensive and useless, see?

But there is good news for those who prefer the familiarity of a first name basis with their favorite carbon-based baristas. The robots have names. “Jarvis” is the machine that positions orders for customer pickup

But so you don't feel bad, we'll give the robots some humanity too.

“It’s more efficient than having a normal barista do it by hand,” said Scelzi. “It knows how long it takes a cup to be filled. It knows where to place it.”

And a person apparently doesn't know these things...

While the company is in beta, visitors will likely interact with at least a few organic life forms at the registers. Just don’t call them baristas.

Organic life forms - how insulting. Why not just call us people?

Clearly, we are being conditioned to think we are inferior so that the robot revolution is accepted easier. What isn't mentioned is that the robot can only execute a specific program - don't expect anything responsive from them. But that is the way these cafes are supposed to be designed - you order "X" and get it, that's it - robbing you of the rich world of human communication. They also want to get into other markets:

“We’d like to be able to do burgers and burritos and Chinese food,” he said. “Basically anything that there is like a QSR — a quick serve restaurant — or fast food restaurant that exists today, we would like to be able to do that as well.”

And outcompete them:

Becker hopes those eventual burrito and burger machines can serve a higher quality product than places like McDonald’s or Burger King, but for the same prices, or lower.

So you can expect most food serving places to be mechanized soon. What does that entail? How about not being able to pay with cash:

Customers place their order via Bbox’s mobile web app (an iOS app is in development) or via tablet outside the café. They create a customer profile, including phone number and payment information.

We're being dehumanized and enslaved in the name of progress. How sad.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Brave_Trackers</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Facebook and Twitter trackers whitelisted by Brave Browser</title>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-13-brave_trackers.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-02-13T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Look how they justify themselves: (from https://brave.com/script-blocking-exceptions-update/https://brave.com/script-blocking-exceptions-update/) - https://archive.fo/Qopen"(archive)

Brave aims to maintain a working Web, while reducing or eliminating the invasive tracking that has become so ubiquitous online.

So which one is the priority? Since your site claims it's the privacy...

For example, Facebook and Twitter both contain widgets which web authors can integrate into their online properties. These widgets aim to make it easier for users and publishers to connect by allowing users to authenticate through Facebook or Twitter, rather than creating and maintaining an account with the publisher themselves. The exception list covered by several news outlets allows both of these widget sets to operate on a leash. They can load, but they cannot access local data on the client so as to track the user.

Who gives a shit whether they can access local data? You've now associated your browsing history with your Facebook and Twitter accounts - and you worry about some local data?! There's no worse tracking than the one attached to your name!

For many publisher implementations, blocking the script request would break Facebook-based OAUTH and Facebook likes and shares.

Yes, of course blocking Facebook tracking would mean you can't authenticate through it. And by whitelisting it, Brave choose a working web over the privacy of its users - proving they, like Mozilla, are just another malicious agent pretending otherwise.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_Mother_Arrested</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Mother arrested for calling a trans person a man on Twitter</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
<category term="society"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-10-mother_arrested.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-02-10T21:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Mother arrested for calling a trans person a man on Twitter

https://www.breitbart.com/europe/2019/02/10/uk-mother-arrested-in-front-of-children-for-calling-trans-person-a-man-on-twitter/ https://archive.fo/T7VeM

38-year-old Kate Scottow, of Hitchin, Hertfordshire, said she was “arrested in my home by three officers, with my autistic ten-year-old daughter and breastfed 20-month-old son present”

I was then detained for seven hours in a cell with no sanitary products (which I said I needed)

So, according to the elites, posting some alleged insults on the Internet is worse than storming someone's house, kidnapping him in front of his children and throwing him into a cell unfit for an animal ("no sanitary products"). Imagine the stress on the chlidren, especially the breastfed one who's fully dependent on his mother after all. Not only that - she's had her DNA and fingerprints taken; say something the elites don't like? Prepare to go into their database and be "suspicious" forever! They also took away her laptop and mobile phone and didn't give it back after more than two months. But the most important thing is - as I spoke in ../ghost/technological_slavery.html"technological slavery - that this was only allowed to happen because that's the nature of the non-anonymous Internet. If this was said in real life, nothing could have happened to her. So the lesson is, don't post anything attached to your real name on the web. It might come back to bite you in the ass.
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_Kenya_DNA_ID</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) Kenyan government mandates DNA linked national ID</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2019-02-09-kenya_dna_id.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-02-09T21:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
Kenyan government mandates DNA linked national ID

https://blog.mozilla.org/netpolicy/2019/02/08/kenya-government-mandates-dna-linked-national-id-without-data-protection-law/ https://web.archive.org/save/https://blog.mozilla.org/netpolicy/2019/02/08/kenya-government-mandates-dna-linked-national-id-without-data-protection-law/

The rebranded, National Integrated Identity Management System (NIIMS) now requires all Kenyans, immigrants, and refugees to turn over their DNA, GPS coordinates of their residential address, retina scans, iris pattern, voice waves, and earlobe geometry before being issued critical identification documents.

This is a clear step towards the kind of world I've described in my ./technological_slavery.html"Technological slavery article. Since you need ID to do anything pretty much (unless you go live in the woods), you will have to give up all the above data. Imagine the complete slavery and hopelessness that could result. Intelligent cameras will easily detect you by the earlobe geometry, and the voice data might even identify you through an anonymously uploaded YouTube video. Finally, they might simply replace IDs altogether with the iris scans and such - creating a world where anyone can be turned off at the elites' whim. For now this is just Kenya (a test run?), but they will for sure bring this system to other countries eventually.



</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_AI_Poop_Scan</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) AI toilets will scan your poop to diagnose your ailments</title>
<category term="AI"></category>
<category term="society"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2018-12-21-ai_poopscan.html"></link>
  <updated>2018-12-21T21:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>

AI toilets will scan your poop to diagnose your ailments

https://www.cnet.com/news/ai-toilets-scan-your-poop-to-diagnose-medical-ailments/
https://archive.fo/6XilJ

Imagine smart toilets in the future that will be analyzing human waste in real time every day. You don't need to be going to visit a physician every six months. If any sign of disease starts showing up, you'll be able to catch it much faster because of urine analysis and stool analysis.

Again, more ../ghost/technological_slavery.html"technological slavery. Will this actually help people? I can imagine it being used to scare you into thinking you've got some imaginary disease and need an expensive drug. Even if it is not intented to be used this way, it will be easier to worry about some disease you allegedly have if you


</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_AI_Lie_Detector</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) AI-powered lie detector will question travellers at EU borders</title>
<category term="AI"></category>
<category term="society"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2018-11-01-ai_bordercontrol.html"></link>
  <updated>2018-10-25T21:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
AI-powered lie detector will question travellers at EU borders

https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2018/11/01/ai-lie-detector-eu-borders/
https://archive.fo/UoUIr

Early tests of the system have resulted in 76 percent accuracy, so well below where it needs to be. iBorderCtrl hopes to increase that to 85 percent.

This one means lost jobs, but more importantly, it will be more demeaning, dehumanizing (imagine having your facial expressions analyzed by a machine...) When this gets good enough, I can see it being very hard to fool.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_News_AI_Art</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(news) AI art sells for $432,500</title>
<category term="AI"></category>
<category term="society"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/news/2018-10-25-ai_portrait.html"></link>
  <updated>2018-10-25T13:00:00Z</updated>
   <content>
AI art sells for $432,500

https://www.christies.com/features/A-collaboration-between-two-artists-one-human-one-a-machine-9332-1.aspx https://archive.fo/voNUT

We found that portraits provided the best way to illustrate our point, which is that algorithms are able to emulate creativity

Another one of supposed creative human endeavors goes down, supporting the thesis in my ../ghost/ai.html"AI article.
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_Libertarianism_Entry</id>
  <title>(article) Refuting Libertarianism (latest update: split and updated the new section)</title>
<category term="capitalism"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
<category term="society"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/libertarianism.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-07-19T21:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>
Wars, propaganda, surveillance, taxes, draconian laws...the ways the governments are exploiting the people are numerous and the situation is only getting worse. This has increased the popularity of an ideology that aims to answer these problems - talking about Libertarianism here, of course. However - while the intentions of many of its proponents are surely good - it has mostly missed the mark and is in fact helping the elites accomplish their malicious plans. Though some of its tenets are valuable - as a whole, Libertarianism - similar to Freetardism - pretends to support our freedom but chains us instead. However, this one is way more important, because it concerns the actual, physical world.

Split up the "Libertarianism provides freedom only to the capitalists" section so that it is more readable. Also added more info.

</content>
</entry>


<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_Law_Entry</id>
  <title>(article) The Enemy Who Surpasses The Law (latest update: expanding the folly of politics)</title>
<category term="slavery"></category>
<category term="society"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/enemylaw.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-05-31T23:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>


The Enemy Who Surpasses The Law

These "crimes" you all speak so seriously of... To me, this has all been nothing more than a game.

Ted Kaczynski, the author of influential essays such as Technological Slavery, is rotting in a high-security prison for life for killing 3 people. Meanwhile...

Massive update to The folly of politics section! Go check it out - lots of good info IMO.


</content>
</entry>


<entry>
<id>DigDeeperHowCapitalismKillsEverything</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) How capitalism destroys everything (latest update: crusade against fangames and mods)</title>
<category term="capitalism"></category>
<category term="society"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/capitalismcancer.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-04-30T14:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

How capitalism destroys everything

Shopping

The entire store-shopping experience is tightly controlled to fuel endless consumption. Let's start with the free samples being given away sometimes. The word will quickly spread that a certain store is giving out free samples and more people will be coming there. They might be compelled to buy more of the product then, when otherwise they would never have looked at it. I mean, do you think the capitalists would give away stuff just for nothing? No way - actually, it is scientifically proven that free samples are an effective way to increase sales...

Added "Crusade against fangames and mods" to video game section.

</content>
</entry>


<entry>
<id>DigDeeperBrowsersEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) How to choose a browser for everyday use? (latest update:PM section)</title>
<category term="internet"></category>
  <category term="software"></category>
  <category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/browsers.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-07-05T22:00:00Z</updated>
   <summary>Let's start with the basics. What is the point of a web browser? Originally, it was to be able to read HTML documents, but since then, the Web has changed massively, and modern browsers need to satisfy more demands...

	Added some info about the recent Firefox security issue which Pale Moon wasn't affected by.
   </summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperLiftingTheVeilEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Lifting the veil - how to test browsers for spyware (latest update: fixing Chrome instructions)</title>
<category term="internet"></category>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>

  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/liftingtheveil.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-05-28T01:00:00Z</updated>
   <summary>Privacy support is one of the chief criteria upon which users pick (or should, anyway) a web browser. Often, a person's opinion of a browser's privacy is manufactured by assumptions, marketing talk, or its privacy policy (which can be hard to read and understand, omit information or outright lie). Wouldn't it be great if we had a way to prove whether a browser actually cares about your privacy, or just bullshits its way through? Fortunately, there is a powerful tool to see exactly what a browser does behind your back, and I'm going to present it to you right now. Let's lift the veils!

   Updated instructions for Chrome-based browsers.</summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperAddonsEntryUpdate2</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Essential privacy (and other) addons (latest update: Redirect Bypasser)</title>
<category term="internet"></category>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/addons.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-07-05T22:00:00Z</updated>

   <summary>If you've read the article How to choose a browser for everyday use, you know that most of their functionalty comes from extensions. So much that, if you've had certain ones for a long time, a browser will seem unusable to you without them. But which ones should we choose, and which ones to avoid? That's exactly what you will learn in this article...

	Added Redirect Bypasser.
   </summary>

</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperEmailEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) E-mail providers - which one to choose? (latest update: more dirt on secmail and proton)</title>
<category term="internet"></category>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/email.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-07-18T07:00:00Z</updated>

<summary>
E-mail sucks but is a necessary evil for now. What should be taken into account while choosing a provider? The most important thing is their privacy policy - as in, what data do they collect and store, and for how long - as well as whom they share it with and under what conditions. Of course, privacy policies should not be automatically trusted - some red flags to watch out for are: too much secretiveness, too much privacy salesmanship, contradictory claims. Always search the Internet for possible breaches that the service in question might have had! Other criteria to consider are: whether the provider supports mail clients (webmail is terrible all around, and takes control out of your hands); the possibility of signing up through Tor / a VPN; and whether its free or paid (though a good paid one is better than a shitty free one; don't worry - the best ones in this report are actually free). Another thing you might want to take into account is how likely is the service to last - if it's been around for 10 years, it's pretty safe to say it will be around for another ten. A single guy running a provider is a ticking time bomb. What about encryption? In-built encryption I consider mostly an illusion - there are various ways of implementing it, but none as robust as PGP with your own keys. And, of course, all of those require webmail, while PGP can be used with mail clients (some, like Claws Mail, even have built-in support). Okay, enough of the introductory bullshit - let's move on to the actual providers!

Updated ProtonMail and Secmail.pro again
</summary>

</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperForumEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Forum Classification Project (latest update: RIP 8chan))</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/forums.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-08-16T07:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

Hey, we're already rating browsers, mail providers, addons...so why not forums? After all, since most of the discussion has moved to giant corpo platforms such as Twitter and Facebook, it is particularly important to find a way to separate yourself from those. The most important criteria will be what is required to register and post. Why is recaptcha so penalized? Simply, it is heavily exploitative - pretty much making you into a dog performing tricks for its master ("Hey Spike, show me the fire hydrants! Good boy...now the crosswalks!"). And if you screw up, it's back to the drawing board, you bad doggie you. You have no idea when the reward (being allowed to register) is coming either - maybe your master will be forgiving and force you to perform only three tricks this time? Low tier is the best rating a forum with recaptcha can get.

8chan is dead and likely won't be back.


</content>
</entry>


<entry>
<id>DigDeeperFakeInitiativesEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Fake privacy / security initiatives (latest update: Who Has Your Back?)</title>
<category term="internet"></category>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/fake_initiatives.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-06-22T14:00:00Z</updated>

<summary>Beware of false prophets, which come to you in sheep’s clothing, but inwardly they are ravening wolves.

Added EFF's recent "Who has your back?" report.</summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperMozillaEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Mozilla - Devil Incarnate (latest update: userchrome.css removal)</title>
<category term="internet"></category>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/mozilla.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-05-26T07:00:00Z</updated>

<summary>If you haven't been living under a rock for the last decade or so, you will at least know Mozilla as the developer of the popular Firefox web browser. Of course, if you've been reading this website a little, you'd guess that there is a darker story behind Mozilla. There is no bigger example of a corporation pretending to be your friend while being your worst enemy. And you don't have to dig too deep to prove it (but we will in this article!) - just get past the skin-deep veil of Mozilla's deception and you reveal a greedy, controlling, sneaky, deceptive, abusive, data hoarding, disempowering, doublespeaking, vile spawn of Satan. So what makes Mozilla different than Google, Microsoft and such? Well, it's the facade of course; they campaign against all the sins they themselves partake in! And it is this facade which I will smash in this article, little by little...

Added removal of userchrome.css as another anti-control scheme.</summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperNinjaEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Ninja's guide to the Internet (latest update: UFW VPN setup)</title>
<category term="internet"></category>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/ninja.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-06-20T16:00:00Z</updated>

<summary>
There's probably hundreds of "guides to Internet privacy" out there now, and most of them are terrible. They recommend browsers from evil companies like Mozilla Firefox; E-mail providers that collect LOTS of your data, such as Mailfence or Runbox; useless or malicious addons like Privacy Badger or NoScript; communication software that ask for your phone number like Signal or Telegram; suspicious VPNs like Proton; care too much about where a service is hosted instead of its policies or functionality; fall for false advertising; have "sponsored" recommendations; ignore very good providers and fail to mention essential things that you SHOULD do. My aim here is to create an ultimate guide which will hopefully not suffer from any of these issues. And the best thing is, you can do everything here for free! Why the Ninja's guide? Well, they hide in the shadows. And it sounds fucking cool, doesn't it?

Added UFW firewall instructions to prevent VPN leaks.</summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperSoftwareEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Useful Linux software you might not know about</title>
  <category term="software"></category>
  <category term="linux"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/software.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-06-01T06:00:00Z</updated>

<summary>
No introduction, just a list of software.

Added Liferea.
</summary>
</entry>



<entry>
<id>DigDeeperSalixEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Salix OS - a hidden gem among Linux distributions</title>
  <category term="software"></category>
  <category term="linux"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/salix.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-10T17:00:00Z</updated>

<summary>
A little backstory. I've been a Linux user since 2007. Some time earlier I read about it in a magazine, but didn't have a way to get it. Finally we've got the Internet, and I ordered a Ubuntu 7.10 CD from shipit.ubuntu.com - they used to send them for free, but have long been defunct. That started my long Linux journey. Next was switching from Ubuntu to Kubuntu (loved KDE 3!), and when they switched to the (IMO) terrible KDE 4, after a while I decided I can't bear with this, and sought another distro.
</summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperFreetardismEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Refuting Freetardism (latest update: FOSS problems and how to fix them)</title>
  <category term="software"></category>
  <category term="philosophy"></category>
  <category term="ethics"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/freetardism.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-04-06T09:00:00Z</updated>

<summary>
A certain ideology has recently (or not so recently) taken the tech communities by storm. Lots of minds have been insidiously captured by it, and ted towards the wrong path, so I wanted to try my hand in refuting it, since no one else seems to be doing it. But first things first - what actually is freetardism? Added (probably final) section "FOSS problems - and how to fix them"
</summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperDesignEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Principles of bad software design </title>
  <category term="software"></category>
  <category term="design"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/design.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-03-10T17:00:00Z</updated>

<summary>
We encounter them everyday, but have learned to ignore or tolerate them - yet they keep popping up like moles, claiming our favorite software. Sometimes we do not know how exactly to describe the flaws - just intuitively realize that something is wrong here. In this article I will try to more methodically point out the numerous bad design decisions, the popular offenders as well as programs who have managed to avoid them.
</summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperWindowsEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) What Linux struggles with (latest update: title change+some content)</title>
  <category term="software"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/windows.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-06-09T08:00:00Z</updated>

<summary>
I've been a Linux user since 2007, and since that time only used Windows sporadically - mostly on other people's computers. The long experience with Linux has allowed me, however, to spot some flaws that have for some reason gone unnoticed by the developers and even by the users. And since no one else mentions them, I will be happy to take on that job.

Title changed to "What Linux struggles with" since I don't really want to praise Windows. Lots of content modified and added.
</summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperLinuxEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Linux Essentials (latest update: how to copy your system elsewhere)</title>
  <category term="software"></category>
  <category term="linux"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/linux.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-06-10T18:30:00Z</updated>

<summary>
...Or more accurately, the things I do after installing a Linux system to make my experience more comfortable. Even with such a user-friendly distro as Salix (which this guide will assume - but most of it can be adapted to other distros), it is easy to get overwhelmed, especially for a recent Windows refugee. So, hopefully this article will provide some tion and save you time, effort, and possible frustration for when you break something and / or have to install Linux on another machine.

Added instructions on how to copy your current system setup to another computer.
</summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeperBotnetEntry</id>
  <link rel="icon" href = "../favicon.ico"></link><title>(article) Avoiding "The Botnet" - impossible? (latest update: Tor section)</title>
  <category term="software"></category>
  <category term="linux"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/linux.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-08-19T06:00:00Z</updated>

<summary>
Avoiding "The Botnet" - impossible?

People these days worry more and more often about escaping what I will call "The Botnet" in this article - just a "meme" way of describing mass surveillance. Websites have been created describing spyware and alternatives to it. Replacements for social services, instant messaging, VoIP, etc. already exist. You can use anonymizers like the Tor network or a VPN to hide from your ISP. There are ways to privately share files and host websites as well. But are all those effective - and more importantly - is this the core of the botnet - or maybe we're going after this entirely the wrong way?

Clarified a few things in the Tor section thanks to feedback from a friend.
</summary>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_SearchEngineEntry</id>
  <title>(article) Search Engines - which one to choose? (latest update: StartPage)</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="privacy"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/search.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-08-18T06:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

Search Engines - which one to choose?

Can't really avoid them, so might as well put some effort into choosing a good one. Let's get the analysis started then! ...

Startpage rewritten.
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_CapitalismWillDie</id>
  <title>(article) Capitalism will die - but will it take us with it? (latest update: various)</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="slavery"></category>
<category term="capitalism"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/capitalism.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-06-07T09:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

Go to school. Go to work. Earn money. Pay for housing, food, entertainment, whatever. Repeat. Most of us know this system too well. But will it last forever?

Somehow forgot to add this one. Updated with some new info.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_GameReviews</id>
  <title>(article) Short video game reviews (latest update: Secret of Mana PSVITA)</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="vidya"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/shortgamereviews.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-07-25T06:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

This article will contain reviews of games that I either don't think deserve a long one, or didn't bother to write one yet. This will be updated whenever I play a new game; some of these might also get proper reviews later, so watch this space.

Another missed article - Secret of Mana (PS Vita) review added today.

</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DigDeeper_Salix_German</id>
  <title>(translation) Salix OS - ein verstecktes Juwel unter den Linux-Distributionen</title>
<category term="technology"></category>
<category term="software"></category>
<category term="linux"></category>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/salixger.html"></link>
  <updated>2019-04-30T09:00:00Z</updated>
  <content>

Eine kleine Hintergrundgeschichte. Ich bin Linux-Nutzer seit 2007. Einige Zeit vorher habe ich darüber in einem Magazin gelesen, aber hatte keinen Weg, es zu bekommen. Endlich haben wir Internet gekriegt, und so bestellte ich dann eine Ubuntu 7.10 CD von shipit.ubuntu.com - sie hatten diese einst kostenlos versendet, aber bestehen schon lange nicht mehr. Damit startete meine lange Linux-Reise. Als nächstes kam das Wechseln von Ubuntu to Kubuntu (ich habe KDE 3 geliebt!), und als sie zu der (mMn) schrecklichen KDE 4 gewechselt sind, habe ich nach einer Weile entschieden, dass ich das nicht mehr ertragen kann, und suchte nach einer anderen Distribution.

</content>
</entry>

</feed>
