,
1: 1 captioning. Live passages may contain errors.
Good evening, welcome to "10vor10".
Terror comes back in Spain.
What triggers the attack in Spain.
Why the breakdown in Germany
Is not the only construction site on the central route.
The background to taking over the free local newspapers.
And in our focus: Blockchain, a technology,
Which could fundamentally alter our world, just like the World Wide Web.
Not again. To Nice, Paris, London, Berlin
It is now in the middle of the Barcelona holiday season.
And the Ramblas, the pedestrian mile, where every tourist walks along,
Where people sit in cafes, drink aperitif.
In the late afternoon, terrorists have attacked.
A truck rushes into a crowd.
So far there are at least 12 dead and dozens of injured.
It is right in the heart of the popular Las Ramblas shopping district.
A white van rushes into a crowd,
Runs snake lines, tears passers-by with him,
Leaves dead and injured.
The driver fled on foot, leaving the white van behind.
First I've heard a lot of people  screaming.
Then I saw the van  across the boulevard.
Everywhere people were  on the floor.
It was cruel.  A terrible image.
The emergency services evacuate shops and houses
Around the place of the attack.
Metro stations are closed.
An array of antiterror forces comes from home at home.
Later the Catalan authorities confirmed:
Two suspects are caught.
A stop in the heart of the tourist city of Barcelona -
Quite unexpectedly,
Says our South-East Europe correspondent Erwin Schmid.
The Spanish authorities were late.  testen since the attack in Nice
in high alertness.
I personally had the impression that  that too the police presence
at neuralgic points,  just like the Ramblas,
where many tourists are staying, .
There were also concrete threats  this spring
from the Islamic state,  but also from El Qaeda in the Maghreb,
that Spain could get into the crossroads  the terrorists.
This also shows the fact that in  Spain within the last year
almost 200 presumed islamist  terrorists were arrested.
So yes, you were in Spain  in high alertness.
The IS-Terrormiliz has on the Internet
The terrorist attack in Barcelona.
One of the soldiers of the so-called Islamic state
Had carried out the act, it was said.
We are now switching to Barcelona, ​​the free journalist Julietmacher.
Can you hear me?
Hello?
Good evening, Fraumacher.
Now it works.
They are near the crime scene.
What is the situation like?
Good evening.
The location is still not  defused.
I was still at a  other place, near the
Ramblas.
There were also all streets  blocked. The whole Ramblas are
locked.
People have to make big detours .
On the other side of the Ramblas,  here, everything is still locked.
You can see again and again  Polizeiautos and hospitals.
The location is tense.
People are also very  resolved and affected.
Today I spoke to people , which are directly seen
,
neither vice zigzag over the  Ramblas before.
I've talked to people who saw  injured and dead.
Nurses who were trying to take care of the people .
The police informed very hesitantly.
Why this restraint?
I think the reason for the  restraint is,
that you did not want to spread panic .
The police spoke quite a long time  only from a dead.
However, after seeing various  eyewitnesses,
that there were guaranteed several dead .
One spoke of three presumed  offenders.
The police, who told me  Colleagues, had the perpetrators
intermittently out of sight  lost.
One has been reluctant to let any panic arise.
It is holiday season.
The city is full and especially  the Ramblas meaningful.
There is day and night a come and go .
There was also panic to prevent .
There is much speculation about the perpetrators.
What is it about it?
As the information comes also  very sparse.
30 minutes ago has the Catalan  Minister President
given a press conference.
There was two of the  speech.
Newspapers write, however, one of the  offenders is on the run
in the gun exchange with the police  killed.
One of the perpetrators was arrested.
The other is not  if it is the third offender
or the one who was shot  -
is from Morocco.
He has lived in the province of Girona  relax.
About the events in Barcelona we keep you on the internet
Under srf.ch/news and in the "Tagesschau Nacht".
To our focus:
A currency, which is only virtual,
A currency without coins and notes,
With which one can do everything: shopping, acting, speculating.
This sounds abstract to many, but is increasingly reality.
Digital currencies boom,
Most notably the most famous among them, the Bitcoin.
So has become the price of a bitcoin in recent years
From a few francs to more than 4,000 francs.
So there is goldgrass tuning around the crypt.
The city of Zug also wants to make a contribution
And is now recommended as Crypto Valley.
To the hype about Bitcoin - Marcel Niedermann.
Even the traders are amazed:
At one of the largest Bitcoin exchanges in Switzerland in Zug
The staff have all hands full.
Obviously, we are in the middle of  a market that tends upward,
where prices are rising.
In the last two weeks  the Bitcoin course has risen rapidly,
from 2'500 to over $ 4,000.
Two years ago these brokers acted
Bitcoins in the volume of $ 20 million a year.
Today are also sometimes times individual orders
Of over $ 100 million.
Cryptry is a goldgrass mood.
The city of Zug also wants to participate in the boom:
She wants to be a Crypto Valley,
A center for blockchain technology.
This also interests Federal Councilor Johann Schneider-Ammann.
He sees potential in the cryptic diet.
I'm assuming  that it's more than a hype.
I think it is a development,  which will be sustainable.
This new instrument, this  new model,
this networking  and linking model has future.
For transactions with conventional currencies
A bank is always connected.
This is different for cryptics like Bitcoin.
Here, money is directly and encrypted
Between two persons.
Thus, the crypt diet is not subject to any control by central banks.
So that the transfer is nevertheless safe,
Each transaction is logged in a type of register.
This register stores simultaneously on thousands of computers worldwide.
They communicate with each other continuously
And thus control each other.
Bitcoins are similar to gold in their total quantity limited.
If demand increases,
This affects the course of the virtual currency.
And this demand is now greater than ever.
There are both companies  and institutions as well as private.
People used to buy  from the technology scene
small amounts of bitcoin.
Today, banks  and asset managers are entering.
And va  also very well-off people,
which was not the case before.
A private bank in Zurich has been offering equipment in Bitcoin since July.
It had been overrun by inquiries,
Says the responsible manager.
Particularly very wealthy customers, who invest their money broadly,
Showed great interest.
The price,  the course of the Bitcoin
and its nature, the digital,  the cryptobased approaches,
do not correlate  with other investment forms
and can thus contribute to the famous  diversification effect.
Bitcoin as a speculative currency and an alternative to known systems.
Meanwhile, other banks have cryptos.
However, not only speculators have interest in Bitcoin.
Venezuela: Bitcoin has been particularly in demand this past week.
One reason is probably the strong money depreciation
The domestic currency Bolivar.
Bitcoin is also strongly traded in China.
There is limited trade in foreign exchange,
Capital movements are controlled by the government.
With the crypt diet, people can circumvent the controls.
Be it as an escape from state interference
Or to bet on price gains.
Va speculation drives the price up.
This entails high risks.
If there is much speculation,  when the journey goes down,
it is not possible to exclude,
certain investors are again saying goodbye to this topic.
Then the value of  drops again quickly.
Bitcoin is no longer only playwright
From a few technology affiliates.
Beneficiaries who bet on the crypt diet,
Continue the myth of Bitcoin - until further notice.
Anyone who invented Bitcoin has not been clarified to date.
Clearly, however, is: Dieselbe mysterious figure
Has also developed the related technology.
A technology that could revolutionize the world.
Jean Francois Tanda.
Blockchain is the technology,
On which the digital currency Bitcoin runs.
While the future of Bitcoin is uncertain, it is safe to say:
The technology behind the decentralized database will survive.
This is the special thing about the Blockchain:
It saves all past transactions forever in blocks,
Which are lined up in a chain
And are no longer changeable.
This chain of blocks is stored on countless computers,
Which are constantly synchronized and contain the same information.
Unlike central databases
No one can change the content unilaterally,
Since the computers involved would hit the alarm,
To ward off such an attack.
A blockchain application is already available as insurance -
If flights are canceled or delayed.
This is followed by Etherisc from ETH graduate Stephan Karpischek.
His start-up will soon be moving into the Crypto Valley.
On the application you enter flight number, flight date,
Concludes a policy and pays for the crypt diet Ether.
If there is a delay,
A lump sum will be paid out automatically.
But Stephan Karpischek wants even more:
He wants to use the blockchain to mix the insurance market.
The insurance company  must make a profit.
It must generate profit.
A blockchain based  insurance
does not have to make any profit.
And the conditions under which  pays the insurance,
are fixed.
They are poured into software  and are no longer editable.
Anyone can review these  conditions, check
and the insurance  proves provably in the event of damage.
And who finances this?
Finance  the other participants.
That's what we know today as  Peer-to-Peer Insurance
and most likely  with a cooperative model.
Another example, which does not yet exist in practice,
But many come to see is car leasing,
Which could be fully automated with Blockchain in the future.
The driver pays his leasing fee on a blockchain.
This communicates with the car
And confirms the payment receipt.
The car can be started.
Device of the driver with his payment in arrears,
The blockchain signals this to the car. The car is blocked.
Only when the due money has arrived,
The driver can drive away again.
Daniel Diemers is a programmer and strategy consultant.
He has been dealing with Blockchain for years.
Technology is going to be more and more popular, he says.
A good example: You always  from land registry offices.
In Georgia  is today a blockchain live,
on the the entire  public hand, the governments
register your transactions.
There are other examples  in the area art -
you can register artworks fake-  cher on the blockhain.
This will also be the really span-  application possibilities.
Whenever I want to check in a  tab,
that something  can not be falsified,
will find blockchain  big spread.
Such a register application already exists today for diamonds.
For proof of origin and for combating blood diamonds.
The company Everledger records the precious stones
And gives them a digital DNA.
One million diamonds are already registered on a blockchain.
Thus, origin and authenticity of the diamonds
At any time.
Algorithms of blockchain replace faulty people,
But today we are only at the beginning.
mid-nineties  was web technology
also for many a book  with seven seals, very difficult.
In the phase  we are now using blockchain.
The blockchain, it seems, will not replace all the previous ones,
But change a lot.
It could be according to the World Wide Web
The next revolution with great effect.
There are only some twisted tracks,
But the rich to the railway traffic on the main route at all,
The North-South axis.
Va the freight traffic suffers from the collapse of the line at Karlsruhe,
Caused by tunneling.
The break is certainly not
The only construction site on the alpine transversal
And quasi the icing on the many problems,
Which always show up when the route is extended. Christian Rensch.
Here the transport containers,
At the loading station Rothrist.
360 containers are up to date, three times more than usual.
This is because the transport via the rail is blocked,
Carrier Ulrich Giezendanner
The lock in the far Rastatt clearly shows:
The location is much more dramatic,  than you think.
Now she tapers.
We still had goods  that was stored in the containers.
Now it's getting better:  There are bottlenecks,
and that will intensify in the next  three, four days massively.
The logistics company Giezendanner
Drives 70% of its goods on the rail.
But by the full lock in Germany
The Swiss rail freight transport is also stuttering.
Concern also with the competent Federal Office of Transport.
It is  a serious situation.
The situation is at the moment  not dramatic,
but the longer  the goods stow,
the greater the impact.
This will mainly affect the  producing industry,
which depends on regular deliveries .
If the goods can not be delivered on a  other way,
be that about alternative railroads  or with load weighing,
some companies could  get in trouble.
The bent tracks of Rastatt.
An image that is unworthy of a high-speed train.
Germany's leading striker in North-South rail freight traffic
Is interrupted.
Instead of 200 freight trains daily there is nothing here for days.
Debt is a new tunnel under the track bed.
Today the tunnel was begun to be filled with concrete.
Whether the 18 million expensive tunnel boring machine can still be saved,
Is uncertain.
But disabilities of the north-south axis are not only present in Rastatt.
Construction sites and bottlenecks
Are on the agenda for alpine freight transport.
In Germany, the entire Rhine valley railway is currently under construction
On four tracks. But it also hurts in Switzerland:
The Bözbergtunnel between Schinznach and Effingen
Had a backlog of three months.
Here a second double burr is built.
Even during the construction of the Maroggia Tunnel,
Three to five months delay according to the last report of the Swiss Confederation.
At present, another access route through the Alps is also blocked:
The Italian Luino axis at Lake Maggiore is being expanded.
But the other routes can not swallow the traffic.
Manuel Herrmann of the Alpen Initiative is therefore criticizing.
The relocation goal of alpine freight transport
From the road to the rail he sees threatened,
If the railways do not seriously tackle the problems
And better coordinate their construction sites.
You have  problems all summer
with the coordination  of the different construction sites.
This has been a problem for a long time  in rail freight traffic.
In the long term, it is certainly important to communicate more,
the coordination  also improves between countries.
Apart from such unpredictable  events it is so:
One would like to increase the cooperation.
It is getting better,  but we are still not at the destination.
Meanwhile, the time is running for many companies.
The container contents are not indefinitely durable.
Of course we have big problems:
We have thermograms,  we have 200 ° C hot concrete
and that will be hard,  if you can not heat it.
Now we have containers,  which are somewhere on the orbit,
and that could be hard.
This will lead to massive  damage claims.
The route at Rastatt will be free again on 26 August,
But today this was not confirmed by Deutsche Bahn.
The Swiss actor Rene Quellet
Died at the age of 86 years.
To be legendary: "I bi de Rene, and I saw nut."
As a partner with Franz Hohler
In the program "Spielhaus" of Swiss television.
Additional short news.
The leader of the umbrella protests of Hong Kong three years ago
Are now punished harder.
Between six and eight months they have to go to jail now -
Convicted of "illegal gathering".
Nevertheless, the three very young accused want to continue fighting,
like you said.
The Democratic Movement of Hong Kong
Has lost a lot of momentum.
Heavy forest fires in the center of Portugal
Have included 2,000 inhabitants of a village.
The rescue workers try, by all means,
To bring the flames under control.
This summer
More than 60 people have died in fires.
What does Christoph Blocher have in mind?
Not only do journalists, who have been known since yesterday,
That the "BaZ", in which the SVP strategist is involved,
All 25 titles of the Zehnder Verlag took over and so soon
The whole of Switzerland with free newspapers.
Is Blocher concerned about politics or economic interests?
What is certain is that journalists are renowned publishing houses
As today in Berne protest against austerity measures,
Are the free leaves that Blocher buys,
Still one of the few promising businesses
In the newspaper market. Pasquale Ferrara.
Hardly anyone knows her,
But the history of Zehnder, the publisher's family, goes back to the 19th century.
The great-grandfather is the second,  my father the fourth,
and I the fifth generation.
The youngest sprout has now given the family heritage.
Zehnder has its 25 regional free newspapers
To the Basel media group of Christoph Blocher.
Price unknown.
Can be the publisher for the political objectives of the SVP man
Clamp?
Mr. Blocher  does not like losing money.
He certainly did not invest,  in the end.
If he made these leaves  SVP leaves,
then he would automatically lose  reader.
Then he would immediately  make an SVP sheet
and can save the purchase price .
The "Wiler Nachrichten" are the origin of the family business.
His success is based on local stories
And not on big political issues.
Also this number is according to his recipe:
Stories up close about people you know.
This is the first issue without me.
I have not been in Regiomedia publishing since 36 hrs. .
And the success  has given us right:
If you stay local,  if you have many heads in it,
when you see this,  which arouses emotions,
then you are on the winners side.
Indeed. While many newspapers lose readers,
The Zehnder Group's newspapers have grown slightly in recent years
To more than 850'000.
Such regional free newspapers are economically viable,
Confirms Professor Marc Eisenegger of the University of Zurich.
The purchase is economically not risky for Blocher,
But politically interesting:
If you look at  the whole history,
the development  at the "Basler Zeitung",
also the project,  which we have discussed prominently,
whether it's a foundation  a free Sunday newspaper
could come from Blocher,  then you have to assume,
that this project  also political interests are there.
So I assume that here  substantial political interests
have played a role.
Blocher did not want to give an interview today.
In yesterday's statement,
Political objectives.
To media diversity and media quality it was today in Berne.
Employees of "Bund" and "Berner Zeitung", which belong to TA-Media,
Protested against austerity measures.
Blocher invests, while traditional publishers save.
No coincidence, the professor says:
The context is actually,
the information media today  have a very heavy level.
One can quite well  speak of a media crisis.
The resources break away,  very much money is flowing -
to the global tech giants  like Google and Facebook -
and the editorial offices are  and media houses under Spardruck.
This increases the risk,
that actors with political  interests,
to seize this media system ,
the media  for political interests.
However, publisher Zehnder is convinced:
For political propaganda its titles are not -
With or without blocher.
So much of us. Immediately after "Meteo"
You can continue with "SommerLacher".
Tomorrow, then, my colleague, Susanne Wille welcomes you here.
Have a nice evening and a good night.
SWISS TXT / UT editorial Zurich Tanja Morana, Regina Kolb, Manuela Waldner