<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-22T21:30:38-05:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/</id><title type="html">LiberIT Blog</title><subtitle>Blogging about how we will colonize the cosmos, while promoting diversity and liberty.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">SoundSassin Robot Scifi</title><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/11/22/Soundsassin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SoundSassin Robot Scifi" /><published>2018-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/11/22/Soundsassin</id><content type="html" xml:base="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/11/22/Soundsassin.html">&lt;p&gt;Plink, Plink, goes the submarine under the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir we are on approach to where we believe the robot base to be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Very well.” Says the captain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, we have reached maximum depth, we can not dive any lower.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How much farther down is their base?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“2.4 kilometers, Sir!.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I see. Will our torpedos reach that far down?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We don’t know, they may implode.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why don’t they just hide in the Mariana Trench is they like it so deep? Those
little buggers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, the sonar shows something on approach. It may be a large squid.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A squid, at these depths? Let me see.” The captain strides over and they watch
a small dot grow closer to them. “Are we just moving towards it, or is it also
moving towards us?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m not sure sir, but it seems to be coming in a couple knots faster than the
surrounding debris.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tink, Tink, a metal contact sounds in the hull, it repeats a few more timis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who was that? Why aren’t they reporting in. Don’t they know we are on high
alert?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bur-gi-ni-brup, bur-gu-nu-brip, the sound continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh, Sir, I think we’ve made contact.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What, where?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The’re on the hull.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bjjj, bjip, bjjjj, bjip, plip the hull continues to vibrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The radio crackles, a robotic voice sounds. “Your ship is ours now, turn around,
or your life will become more difficult.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who was that? We’re too deep for radio contact.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They must have latched within range of the antenna.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface of the hull a robot of the Hmik clan hangs on with two circular
magnets. One a speaker, one a microphone. Tink, Tink, another groupie arrives,
Tink, Tink, another, Tink, Tink, and another. The submarine is surrounded,
all sounds can be quadrangulated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bur-gi-ni-brup, bur-gu-nu-brip”, they map the contents of the submarine. Each
unit now has an up to date map of the interior and all the people in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bjjj, bjip, bjjjj, bjip, plip”, familiar with the model of torpedos, they find 
the fuse resonance and force it till it cracks. Torpedos disabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top rider comms the humans aboard, to give them the choice to go home, without
further incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The submarine continues going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;```&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please, we’re not scared of a few burps. Fire the torpedos! That’ll keep them
busy.” The captain raps his fingers on a nearby rail. He waits. “Well, what’s
the matter? Fire them already.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh, sir, it seems the torpedos are all duds. They all failed to deploy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The torpedos are broken.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What else do we have?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sonar, sir”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Explain.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We can get a better reading of where the robot base for future expeditions, 
or we might be able to paint them for an air strike.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay, go ahead”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bjiu, bjiu, bjiu, bjiu, bjiu, the sound grows deafening, several men faint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir! We’re under attack!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can see that!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crackle, static, crackle, static “that was a small taste yes. Would you like
more, or did you want to turn back?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, I intend to turn us around.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, keep on, we have to do something. How are those sonar reports coming, do we
have anything?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man that was at the sonar had fainted, “Sir, I intend to help move the
bodies to sick bay.” someone stands pickup up the sonar man and starts to move
him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, I intend to take over the sonar.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Very well.” the captain answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BJJJJJJJJUUUUUUP, splat. The skull of the man that was about to go for the sonar
and his brains paint the walls, the crew and the captain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Turn back at once!” The captain proclaims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;crackle, crackle, “Wise choice, Captian. You were next, wink.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside the bottom robot snickers, popcorn people, he thinks. The robots stay
latached until the submarine leaves their territory, then they silently detach
and drift back to their patrols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-end&quot;&gt;The End&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book was partially inspired by the book “Turn the ship around” by David
Marquet, and partially by the ancient sound technology involved in the building
of the pyramids. Something that certainly submarine robot cities would be able
to employ in order to protect themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story is CC-BY-SA, so feel free to share and expand upon it, or to reuse
theme attributes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Plink, Plink, goes the submarine under the water.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Science of Getting Rich</title><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/11/10/Science-of-getting-rich.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Science of Getting Rich" /><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/11/10/Science-of-getting-rich</id><content type="html" xml:base="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/11/10/Science-of-getting-rich.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/342504.The_Science_of_Getting_Rich&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding-right: 20px&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;The Science of Getting Rich&quot; src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1440958184m/342504.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/342504.The_Science_of_Getting_Rich&quot;&gt;The Science of Getting Rich&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/65913.Wallace_D_Wattles&quot;&gt;Wallace D. Wattles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2571618671&quot;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Wonderful book, has an idealist world view which is the inspiration for the “Law of Attraction” and that whole family of books and material. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Most of the things in it I’m already applying, but it helped to bring some others to light. Such as cultivating a creators mindset, and that there is opportunity enough for everyone. One of the best parts for me was that I don’t have to hurry, because hurrying is a competitive mindset, and in a creators mindset we are creating so there is enough for everyone, just beautiful. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also it talks a lot about getting that big vision out in detail and since there is no rush I think I have the time to do it! Just wonderful! &lt;em&gt;hugs&lt;/em&gt; I love this book, and will probably reread it again sometimes in future. At my audio book reading speed it took me less than an hour to get through this short book, also amazing considering how impactful it is.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thank you Wallace Wattles for giving us this precious gem of a book. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/66927353-logan-streondj&quot;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Science of Getting Rich by Wallace D. Wattles My rating: 5 of 5 stars Wonderful book, has an idealist world view which is the inspiration for the “Law of Attraction” and that whole family of books and material. Most of the things in it I’m already applying, but it helped to bring some others to light. Such as cultivating a creators mindset, and that there is opportunity enough for everyone. One of the best parts for me was that I don’t have to hurry, because hurrying is a competitive mindset, and in a creators mindset we are creating so there is enough for everyone, just beautiful. Also it talks a lot about getting that big vision out in detail and since there is no rush I think I have the time to do it! Just wonderful! hugs I love this book, and will probably reread it again sometimes in future. At my audio book reading speed it took me less than an hour to get through this short book, also amazing considering how impactful it is.Thank you Wallace Wattles for giving us this precious gem of a book. View all my reviews</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leaders Eat Last by Simon Sinek</title><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/27/Leaders-Eat-Last.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leaders Eat Last by Simon Sinek" /><published>2018-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/27/Leaders-Eat-Last</id><content type="html" xml:base="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/27/Leaders-Eat-Last.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16144853-leaders-eat-last&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding-right: 20px&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Leaders Eat Last&quot; src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1400881733m/16144853.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16144853-leaders-eat-last&quot;&gt;Leaders Eat Last&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3158574.Simon_Sinek&quot;&gt;Simon Sinek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2571668245&quot;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The most inspirational book on leadership that I’ve read thus far.&lt;br /&gt;One of my main takeaways is that leaders have a social contract they have to upkeep with their people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He also talked about brain chemicals and how competitive environments make people more selfish dopamine junkies.&lt;br /&gt;Wheras cooperative environments foster serotonin and oxytocin, allowing everyone to work together and prosper.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Feeling unsafe and competitive also pumps cortisol and adrenaline which is unhealthy at chronic levels.&lt;br /&gt;Wheras serotonin and oxytocin help improve lifespans.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As leaders we have to foster an environment that promotes feelings of safety and cooperation in the company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He talked about how our Paleolithic roots are what make us work best in safe groups. And that contemporary obsession with stats often leads to bad decisions by dehumanizing the situation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He talked about the importance of culture in creating an atmosphere of cooperation and that the leader sets the tone for an organization. So even a great culture can be corrupted by bad leadership, and a competitive culture can be made good with cooperative leadership.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He talked about the importance of interity AKA truthfulness and how it is essential to trust and being a good leader. Since trust is essential to followers feeling they can rely on their leader.&lt;br /&gt;He also talked about the various generations (great, boomer, x, y) their strengths and weaknesses. Said important thing to watch out for millennials is realising that things take time, and that to get things accomplished we have to do more than raise awareness. We have to act and persist in cooperation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He also talked about how teaching others cooperative leadership is key to maintaining your own. That legacy is the cooperative culture that allows a company to continue succeeding after you’ve left.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That we’re in this together and together we make happy memories, the now and the future.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/66927353-logan-streondj&quot;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great book with easy to understand examples and counter measures.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2 Reciprocation: The Old Give and Take…and Take&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;People feel they need to give back for any gift they receive. Most memorable was how the Hare Krishna’s got rich handing out recycled flowers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another important thing covered was giving concessions whether real or imaginary to motivate others to agree to buy. Best example was the Watergate burglary which was sold to the Republicans as by concession.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3 Commitment and Consistency: Hobgoblins of the Mind&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;About how people tend to be consistent and the small choices they make change their internal self representation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Great example was that by getting PoW to agree that America is not perfect they put them on the road to writing pro communist anti american essays.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;4 Social Proof: Truths Are Us&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Otherwise known as the bandwagon effect it is how by making something seem popular can promote you to go along with it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Best example was how he had trouble getting his three year old to learn to swim, but then found him swimming quite well simply because he saw another three year old swimming. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;5 Liking: The Friendly Thief&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is about where sales people want to pretend to be similar to you in order to get you to like them and want to buy from them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Best example was a car salesman that sent people postcards every month that said ‘I Like You’&lt;br /&gt;6 Authority: Directed Deference&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is about how people will stop making decisions when there is a higher authority.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Best example was that high percentage of nurses went to administer a potentially lethal dose of a medication to a patient simply because someone over the phone claiming to be a doctor told them to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;7 Scarcity: The Rule of the Few&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This was about how a lack of something made it more desirable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Best example was how when the new freedoms Gorbachev gave people were threatened by a coup the people of the Soviet Union rose up and rioted so hard that after only three days the USSR fell.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wow! Impressive book many lessons, I’ve even applied some in my life, like the consistency principle by publicizing my intent to be a virtuous Buddhist I’ve reached a new level of consistency.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/66927353-logan-streondj&quot;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Leaders Eat Last by Simon Sinek My rating: 5 of 5 stars The most inspirational book on leadership that I’ve read thus far.One of my main takeaways is that leaders have a social contract they have to upkeep with their people.He also talked about brain chemicals and how competitive environments make people more selfish dopamine junkies.Wheras cooperative environments foster serotonin and oxytocin, allowing everyone to work together and prosper.Feeling unsafe and competitive also pumps cortisol and adrenaline which is unhealthy at chronic levels.Wheras serotonin and oxytocin help improve lifespans.As leaders we have to foster an environment that promotes feelings of safety and cooperation in the company.He talked about how our Paleolithic roots are what make us work best in safe groups. And that contemporary obsession with stats often leads to bad decisions by dehumanizing the situation.He talked about the importance of culture in creating an atmosphere of cooperation and that the leader sets the tone for an organization. So even a great culture can be corrupted by bad leadership, and a competitive culture can be made good with cooperative leadership.He talked about the importance of interity AKA truthfulness and how it is essential to trust and being a good leader. Since trust is essential to followers feeling they can rely on their leader.He also talked about the various generations (great, boomer, x, y) their strengths and weaknesses. Said important thing to watch out for millennials is realising that things take time, and that to get things accomplished we have to do more than raise awareness. We have to act and persist in cooperation.He also talked about how teaching others cooperative leadership is key to maintaining your own. That legacy is the cooperative culture that allows a company to continue succeeding after you’ve left.That we’re in this together and together we make happy memories, the now and the future. View all my reviews</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Influence: The Psychology of Persuasion</title><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/23/Psychology-of-Persuasion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Influence: The Psychology of Persuasion" /><published>2018-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/23/Psychology-of-Persuasion</id><content type="html" xml:base="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/23/Psychology-of-Persuasion.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28815.Influence&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding-right: 20px&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Influence: The Psychology of Persuasion&quot; src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1391026083m/28815.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28815.Influence&quot;&gt;Influence: The Psychology of Persuasion&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/160932.Robert_B_Cialdini&quot;&gt;Robert B. Cialdini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2562384790&quot;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A great book with easy to understand examples and counter measures.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2 Reciprocation: The Old Give and Take…and Take&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;People feel they need to give back for any gift they receive. Most memorable was how the Hare Krishna’s got rich handing out recycled flowers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another important thing covered was giving concessions whether real or imaginary to motivate others to agree to buy. Best example was the Watergate burglary which was sold to the Republicans as by concession.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3 Commitment and Consistency: Hobgoblins of the Mind&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;About how people tend to be consistent and the small choices they make change their internal self representation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Great example was that by getting PoW to agree that America is not perfect they put them on the road to writing pro communist anti american essays.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;4 Social Proof: Truths Are Us&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Otherwise known as the bandwagon effect it is how by making something seem popular can promote you to go along with it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Best example was how he had trouble getting his three year old to learn to swim, but then found him swimming quite well simply because he saw another three year old swimming. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;5 Liking: The Friendly Thief&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is about where sales people want to pretend to be similar to you in order to get you to like them and want to buy from them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Best example was a car salesman that sent people postcards every month that said ‘I Like You’&lt;br /&gt;6 Authority: Directed Deference&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is about how people will stop making decisions when there is a higher authority.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Best example was that high percentage of nurses went to administer a potentially lethal dose of a medication to a patient simply because someone over the phone claiming to be a doctor told them to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;7 Scarcity: The Rule of the Few&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This was about how a lack of something made it more desirable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Best example was how when the new freedoms Gorbachev gave people were threatened by a coup the people of the Soviet Union rose up and rioted so hard that after only three days the USSR fell.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wow! Impressive book many lessons, I’ve even applied some in my life, like the consistency principle by publicizing my intent to be a virtuous Buddhist I’ve reached a new level of consistency.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/66927353-logan-streondj&quot;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Influence: The Psychology of Persuasion by Robert B. Cialdini My rating: 5 of 5 stars A great book with easy to understand examples and counter measures.2 Reciprocation: The Old Give and Take…and TakePeople feel they need to give back for any gift they receive. Most memorable was how the Hare Krishna’s got rich handing out recycled flowers.Another important thing covered was giving concessions whether real or imaginary to motivate others to agree to buy. Best example was the Watergate burglary which was sold to the Republicans as by concession.3 Commitment and Consistency: Hobgoblins of the MindAbout how people tend to be consistent and the small choices they make change their internal self representation.Great example was that by getting PoW to agree that America is not perfect they put them on the road to writing pro communist anti american essays.4 Social Proof: Truths Are UsOtherwise known as the bandwagon effect it is how by making something seem popular can promote you to go along with it.Best example was how he had trouble getting his three year old to learn to swim, but then found him swimming quite well simply because he saw another three year old swimming. 5 Liking: The Friendly ThiefThis is about where sales people want to pretend to be similar to you in order to get you to like them and want to buy from them.Best example was a car salesman that sent people postcards every month that said ‘I Like You’6 Authority: Directed DeferenceThis is about how people will stop making decisions when there is a higher authority.Best example was that high percentage of nurses went to administer a potentially lethal dose of a medication to a patient simply because someone over the phone claiming to be a doctor told them to.7 Scarcity: The Rule of the FewThis was about how a lack of something made it more desirable.Best example was how when the new freedoms Gorbachev gave people were threatened by a coup the people of the Soviet Union rose up and rioted so hard that after only three days the USSR fell.Wow! Impressive book many lessons, I’ve even applied some in my life, like the consistency principle by publicizing my intent to be a virtuous Buddhist I’ve reached a new level of consistency. View all my reviews</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Universe in a Single Atom: The Convergence of Science and Spirituality by the Dalai Lama</title><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/19/Universe-Atom.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Universe in a Single Atom: The Convergence of Science and Spirituality by the Dalai Lama" /><published>2018-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/19/Universe-Atom</id><content type="html" xml:base="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/19/Universe-Atom.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/100629.The_Universe_in_a_Single_Atom&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding-right: 20px&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;The Universe in a Single Atom: The Convergence of Science and Spirituality&quot; src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1320558690m/100629.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/100629.The_Universe_in_a_Single_Atom&quot;&gt;The Universe in a Single Atom: The Convergence of Science and Spirituality&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/570218.Dalai_Lama_XIV&quot;&gt;Dalai Lama XIV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2570423492&quot;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Largely this is an autobiographical book about the Dalai Lama’s personal journey with science and the fascination he has had for it since his childhood.&lt;br /&gt; It does have some introductory material on how science works and some points of comparison between science and Buddhism.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Near the end it turned into a soft warning regarding the potential dangers of genetic modification.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There were many parts of the book I found quite inspirational especially some of his questions which led me on journeys to find my own answers.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/66927353-logan-streondj&quot;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Universe in a Single Atom: The Convergence of Science and Spirituality by Dalai Lama XIV My rating: 5 of 5 stars Largely this is an autobiographical book about the Dalai Lama’s personal journey with science and the fascination he has had for it since his childhood. It does have some introductory material on how science works and some points of comparison between science and Buddhism.Near the end it turned into a soft warning regarding the potential dangers of genetic modification.There were many parts of the book I found quite inspirational especially some of his questions which led me on journeys to find my own answers. View all my reviews</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lean Startup: How Today’s Entrepreneus Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful Businesses</title><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/14/Frank-Einstein-Antimatter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lean Startup: How Today's Entrepreneus Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful Businesses" /><published>2018-10-14T22:35:47-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-14T22:35:47-04:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/14/Frank-Einstein-Antimatter</id><content type="html" xml:base="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/14/Frank-Einstein-Antimatter.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10127019-the-lean-startup&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding-right: 20px&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;The Lean Startup: How Today's Entrepreneurs Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful Businesses&quot; src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1333576876m/10127019.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10127019-the-lean-startup&quot;&gt;The Lean Startup: How Today’s Entrepreneurs Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful Businesses&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/278960.Eric_Ries&quot;&gt;Eric Ries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2562390318&quot;&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Part one vision, is mostly about startups in early-adopter phase, with lots of experimentation. It helped raise my confidence that I don’t need a perfect product, or even a very good one, just one that works, and then can try it out. &lt;br /&gt;Part two vision is about applying the scientific method an doing A/B testing on everything, also covers a bunch of different ways to pivot, which I think is probably one of the most innovative and best parts of this book. &lt;br /&gt;Part three accelerate has some tips on how to get things accomplished, like using small batches instead of large ones. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The main reason I took off a star is because the title isn’t super accurate, while it does say “lean startup”, it includes a lot of information for mega-corporations as well, and the main message throughout the book is “use the scientific method”.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I think perhaps a more accurate title would be “innovating in business using the scientific method”.&lt;br /&gt;All that said, I have figuring out wasabi A/B testing framework firmly on my todo list, and will schedule some time to figure it out soon. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/66927353-logan-streondj&quot;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Lean Startup: How Today’s Entrepreneurs Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful Businesses by Eric Ries My rating: 4 of 5 stars Part one vision, is mostly about startups in early-adopter phase, with lots of experimentation. It helped raise my confidence that I don’t need a perfect product, or even a very good one, just one that works, and then can try it out. Part two vision is about applying the scientific method an doing A/B testing on everything, also covers a bunch of different ways to pivot, which I think is probably one of the most innovative and best parts of this book. Part three accelerate has some tips on how to get things accomplished, like using small batches instead of large ones. The main reason I took off a star is because the title isn’t super accurate, while it does say “lean startup”, it includes a lot of information for mega-corporations as well, and the main message throughout the book is “use the scientific method”.I think perhaps a more accurate title would be “innovating in business using the scientific method”.All that said, I have figuring out wasabi A/B testing framework firmly on my todo list, and will schedule some time to figure it out soon. View all my reviews</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Frank Einstein and the Antimatter Motor</title><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/12/Lean-Startup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Frank Einstein and the Antimatter Motor" /><published>2018-10-12T22:35:47-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-12T22:35:47-04:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/12/Lean-Startup</id><content type="html" xml:base="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/12/Lean-Startup.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20702011-frank-einstein-and-the-antimatter-motor&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding-right: 20px&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Frank Einstein and the Antimatter Motor (Frank Einstein, #1)&quot; src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1398193499m/20702011.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20702011-frank-einstein-and-the-antimatter-motor&quot;&gt;Frank Einstein and the Antimatter Motor&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/27318.Jon_Scieszka&quot;&gt;Jon Scieszka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2562386065&quot;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My five year old read it in two weeks, it was a fun light read.&lt;br /&gt;While it is a soft sci-fi with many fantastical things happening,&lt;br /&gt;it does include some real science as an entertaining introduction. &lt;br /&gt;For me it checks off all the boxes, it has robots, is educational, &lt;br /&gt;is good for my child’s reading development, and is entertaining. &lt;br /&gt;So I give it 5 stars, well done Jon Scieszka!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/66927353-logan-streondj&quot;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part one vision, is mostly about startups in early-adopter phase, with lots of experimentation. It helped raise my confidence that I don’t need a perfect product, or even a very good one, just one that works, and then can try it out. &lt;br /&gt;Part two vision is about applying the scientific method an doing A/B testing on everything, also covers a bunch of different ways to pivot, which I think is probably one of the most innovative and best parts of this book. &lt;br /&gt;Part three accelerate has some tips on how to get things accomplished, like using small batches instead of large ones. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The main reason I took off a star is because the title isn’t super accurate, while it does say “lean startup”, it includes a lot of information for mega-corporations as well, and the main message throughout the book is “use the scientific method”.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I think perhaps a more accurate title would be “innovating in business using the scientific method”.&lt;br /&gt;All that said, I have figuring out wasabi A/B testing framework firmly on my todo list, and will schedule some time to figure it out soon. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/66927353-logan-streondj&quot;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Frank Einstein and the Antimatter Motor by Jon Scieszka My rating: 5 of 5 stars My five year old read it in two weeks, it was a fun light read.While it is a soft sci-fi with many fantastical things happening,it does include some real science as an entertaining introduction. For me it checks off all the boxes, it has robots, is educational, is good for my child’s reading development, and is entertaining. So I give it 5 stars, well done Jon Scieszka! View all my reviews</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">15 Secrets Successful People Know About Time Management: The Productivity Habits of 7 Billionaires, 13 Olympic Athletes, 29 Straight-A Students, and 239 Entrepreneurs</title><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/10/15-secrets-time-management.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="15 Secrets Successful People Know About Time Management: The Productivity Habits of 7 Billionaires, 13 Olympic Athletes, 29 Straight-A Students, and 239 Entrepreneurs" /><published>2018-10-10T22:35:47-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-10T22:35:47-04:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/10/15-secrets-time-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/hpuk/2018/10/10/15-secrets-time-management.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27139721-15-secrets-successful-people-know-about-time-management&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding-right: 20px&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;15 Secrets Successful People Know About Time Management: The Productivity Habits of 7 Billionaires, 13 Olympic Athletes, 29 Straight-A Students, and 239 Entrepreneurs&quot; src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1444590824m/27139721.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27139721-15-secrets-successful-people-know-about-time-management&quot;&gt;15 Secrets Successful People Know About Time Management: The Productivity Habits of 7 Billionaires, 13 Olympic Athletes, 29 Straight-A Students, and 239 Entrepreneurs&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/8387961.Kevin_Kruse&quot;&gt;Kevin Kruse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2554785503&quot;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is a great time management book that has changed my life in the short time I’ve had it. &lt;br /&gt;The main takeaways for me was to put less emphasis on todo lists and much more on having a calendar schedule. The quote that stuck with me most from here is scheduling your calendar in 15 minute increments will put you in 95th percentile of time organization. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Otherwise I like to review my non fiction books by going through the table of contents. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* The power of 1440&lt;br /&gt; there are 1440 minutes in a day, and every minute counts. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* The Power of Proper Priorities&lt;br /&gt;you gotta select one thing and stick to it&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* Stop making to-do lists – do this instead&lt;br /&gt;schedule stuff on a calendar&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* the procrastination cure&lt;br /&gt;bunch of anti-procrastination tips,&lt;br /&gt;though for me the most powerful has been simply to schedule it,&lt;br /&gt;cause then I do it. Though for others maybe this chapter would be helpful.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* How to Leave the Office at 5:00 – Without Guilt&lt;br /&gt;Basically schedule it. Instead of having todo list, have a schedule.&lt;br /&gt;Then if you have overflow, hire people or outsource. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* Richard Branson’s Secret Productivity Tool&lt;br /&gt;a notebook. A paper notebook and pen, to write ideas when they happen.&lt;br /&gt;Can also be used to take notes in meetings and such.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* Master your email inbox with 321Zero&lt;br /&gt;various tips for minimizing your inbox, and getting through all your emails within 21 minutes or less.&lt;br /&gt;like unsubscribe from mailing lists, and use quick responses. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* Meeting hacks from Google, Apple and Virgin.&lt;br /&gt;Main takeaway for me was that standing meetings are more productive than sit down meetings, want to have as few people as possible, and if you can be walking or moving around during the meeting even better. I’ve since schedules a 15 minute daily huddle with my spouse, so we can talk about any issues that have come up in the day, and schedule things we’re interested in doing. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* One Little Word that Multiplies Success&lt;br /&gt;No. The idea is that saying yes means saying no to other things. &lt;br /&gt;So better to keep that one thing or main goal in focus with everything,&lt;br /&gt;and if this doesn’t benefit that, then say no. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* The Powerful Paraeto Principle&lt;br /&gt;the 80/20 rule. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* The “3 Harvard Questions” That Save 8 Hours a Week&lt;br /&gt;Drop, Delegate, Redesign. &lt;br /&gt;What can I drop or stop doing?&lt;br /&gt;What can I delegate or outsource?&lt;br /&gt;What can I do in a more efficient way?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Notably amongst the entrepreneur responses later in the book, &lt;br /&gt;this was one of the most cited things. To delegate and hire people.&lt;br /&gt;You get the idea, then set up a machine so other people can make it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* Why Twitter Co-Founder Jack Dorsey Themes His Days&lt;br /&gt;A kind of meta-scheduling where each day of the week has a different focus.&lt;br /&gt;Focus Days, Buffer Days (catch up), Free Days (weekends).&lt;br /&gt;Monday Management Day, &lt;br /&gt;Tuesday Product Day (focus day),&lt;br /&gt;Wednesday Marketing PR Day (focus day),&lt;br /&gt;Thursdays Developers and Partners (focus day).&lt;br /&gt;Friday culture and recruiting (buffer day). &lt;br /&gt;Saturday hiking day (Free day),&lt;br /&gt;Sunday reflection day (Free day).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* Don’t Touch! (Until You’re Ready)&lt;br /&gt;promotes “touch it once” mentality, &lt;br /&gt;idea being to finish any task that takes less than 5 minutes immediately,&lt;br /&gt;rather than procrastinate, which would waste more time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* Change Your Morning, Change Your Life&lt;br /&gt;Talks about the importance of having a good morning routine, &lt;br /&gt;and that the most cognitively productive hours are in the morning. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* Energy is Everything&lt;br /&gt;Sleep enough, eat healthy, hydrate, meditate, and exercise. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* The E-3C System: Putting It All Together&lt;br /&gt;Energy, Capture, Calendar, Concentrate. &lt;br /&gt;Energy: stay healthy.&lt;br /&gt;Capture: write it in your notebook.&lt;br /&gt;Calendar: schedule, main goals, theme days, say no to the irrelevant.&lt;br /&gt;Concentrate: one task at a time, no notifications, schedule rest at least once an hour. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is also all the quotes from those billionaires, olympians and entrepreneurs. a quiz and some other extras. well worth the money.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/66927353-logan-streondj&quot;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">15 Secrets Successful People Know About Time Management: The Productivity Habits of 7 Billionaires, 13 Olympic Athletes, 29 Straight-A Students, and 239 Entrepreneurs by Kevin Kruse My rating: 5 of 5 stars This is a great time management book that has changed my life in the short time I’ve had it. The main takeaways for me was to put less emphasis on todo lists and much more on having a calendar schedule. The quote that stuck with me most from here is scheduling your calendar in 15 minute increments will put you in 95th percentile of time organization. Otherwise I like to review my non fiction books by going through the table of contents. * The power of 1440 there are 1440 minutes in a day, and every minute counts. * The Power of Proper Prioritiesyou gotta select one thing and stick to it* Stop making to-do lists – do this insteadschedule stuff on a calendar* the procrastination curebunch of anti-procrastination tips,though for me the most powerful has been simply to schedule it,cause then I do it. Though for others maybe this chapter would be helpful.* How to Leave the Office at 5:00 – Without GuiltBasically schedule it. Instead of having todo list, have a schedule.Then if you have overflow, hire people or outsource. * Richard Branson’s Secret Productivity Toola notebook. A paper notebook and pen, to write ideas when they happen.Can also be used to take notes in meetings and such.* Master your email inbox with 321Zerovarious tips for minimizing your inbox, and getting through all your emails within 21 minutes or less.like unsubscribe from mailing lists, and use quick responses. * Meeting hacks from Google, Apple and Virgin.Main takeaway for me was that standing meetings are more productive than sit down meetings, want to have as few people as possible, and if you can be walking or moving around during the meeting even better. I’ve since schedules a 15 minute daily huddle with my spouse, so we can talk about any issues that have come up in the day, and schedule things we’re interested in doing. * One Little Word that Multiplies SuccessNo. The idea is that saying yes means saying no to other things. So better to keep that one thing or main goal in focus with everything,and if this doesn’t benefit that, then say no. * The Powerful Paraeto Principlethe 80/20 rule. * The “3 Harvard Questions” That Save 8 Hours a WeekDrop, Delegate, Redesign. What can I drop or stop doing?What can I delegate or outsource?What can I do in a more efficient way?Notably amongst the entrepreneur responses later in the book, this was one of the most cited things. To delegate and hire people.You get the idea, then set up a machine so other people can make it.* Why Twitter Co-Founder Jack Dorsey Themes His DaysA kind of meta-scheduling where each day of the week has a different focus.Focus Days, Buffer Days (catch up), Free Days (weekends).Monday Management Day, Tuesday Product Day (focus day),Wednesday Marketing PR Day (focus day),Thursdays Developers and Partners (focus day).Friday culture and recruiting (buffer day). Saturday hiking day (Free day),Sunday reflection day (Free day).* Don’t Touch! (Until You’re Ready)promotes “touch it once” mentality, idea being to finish any task that takes less than 5 minutes immediately,rather than procrastinate, which would waste more time.* Change Your Morning, Change Your LifeTalks about the importance of having a good morning routine, and that the most cognitively productive hours are in the morning. * Energy is EverythingSleep enough, eat healthy, hydrate, meditate, and exercise. * The E-3C System: Putting It All TogetherEnergy, Capture, Calendar, Concentrate. Energy: stay healthy.Capture: write it in your notebook.Calendar: schedule, main goals, theme days, say no to the irrelevant.Concentrate: one task at a time, no notifications, schedule rest at least once an hour. There is also all the quotes from those billionaires, olympians and entrepreneurs. a quiz and some other extras. well worth the money. View all my reviews</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">blogging-git-hooks: Created Jekyll Blog Post and Deploys</title><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/blogging-git-hooks/2018/10/08/blogging-git-hooks-Created-Jekyll-Blog-Post-and-Deploys.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="blogging-git-hooks: Created Jekyll Blog Post and Deploys" /><published>2018-10-08T14:20:49-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T14:20:49-04:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/blogging-git-hooks/2018/10/08/blogging-git-hooks:-Created-Jekyll-Blog-Post-and-Deploys</id><content type="html" xml:base="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/blogging-git-hooks/2018/10/08/blogging-git-hooks-Created-Jekyll-Blog-Post-and-Deploys.html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Managed to get it to create a Jekyll blog post and deploy to website.
Still have to get it to deploy to docker, and then docker-machine
docker-compose pull on the servers.
Also need to get it to post to github the new post.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;+++ b/blogging-git-hook.sh
+# get differences
+headVersion=$(git log |grep ^commit |head -n 1| awk '{print $2}')
+previousVersion=$(git log |grep ^commit |head -n 2 |tail -n 1 | awk '{print $2}')
+newContent=$(git diff &quot;$previousVersion&quot; &quot;$headVersion&quot; |grep ^+|more)
+projectName=$(pwd|sed -e 's/.*\///')
+title=&quot;$projectName: $(git log -n 1|head -n 5|tail -n 1|sed -e 's/^ *//')&quot;
+author=$(git log -n 1| grep Author| sed -e 's/.*://')
+description=$(tail -n $(($(git log -n 1 |wc -l)-5)))
+blogPWD=&quot;$HOME/Documents/blog/liberit-blog&quot;
+# shellcheck disable=SC2001
+safeTitle=$(echo &quot;$title&quot;| sed -e 's/ /-/g') 
+filename=&quot;$(date -I)-$safeTitle.md&quot;
+# generate entry
+{
+echo &quot;---&quot;
+echo &quot;layout: post&quot;
+echo &quot;title: \&quot;$title\&quot;&quot;
+echo &quot;author: $author&quot;
+echo &quot;date: $(date --iso-8601=seconds)&quot;
+echo &quot;categories: $projectName&quot;
+echo &quot;---&quot;
+echo &quot;$description&quot;
+# shellcheck disable=SC2016
+echo '```'
+echo &quot;$newContent&quot;
+# shellcheck disable=SC2016
+echo '```'
+echo &quot;This post was automatically generated from a git commit&quot;
+} &amp;gt; &quot;$blogPWD/_posts/$filename&quot;
+
+# publish
+
+zronhwephbis=&quot;$HOME/ZeroNet&quot;
+hnim=&quot;1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ&quot;
+
+cd &quot;$blogPWD&quot; || exit 1
+bundle exec jekyll build || exit 1
+
+# make docker image
+docker build -t liberit/blog
+
+
+# add to zeronet
+rsync -av _site/ &quot;$zronhwephbis/data/$hnim&quot;
+cd &quot;$zronhwephbis&quot; || exit 1
+./zeronet.py siteSign $hnim
+./zeronet.py sitePublish $hnim
+rsync -av &quot;$zronhwephbis/data/$hnim&quot; zeronet@liberit.ca:data/
+
+# post to twitter
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated from a git commit&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Logan Streondj &lt;logan@liberit.ca&gt;</name></author><summary type="html">Managed to get it to create a Jekyll blog post and deploy to website. Still have to get it to deploy to docker, and then docker-machine docker-compose pull on the servers. Also need to get it to post to github the new post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">blogging-git-hooks: added hashbang</title><link href="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/blogging-git-hooks/2018/10/08/blogging-git-hooks-added-hashbang.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="blogging-git-hooks: added hashbang" /><published>2018-10-08T14:01:54-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T14:01:54-04:00</updated><id>/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/blogging-git-hooks/2018/10/08/blogging-git-hooks:-added-hashbang</id><content type="html" xml:base="/1vLoKesxKQDnLFrmJDoUXyrWX1h2YwSGJ/blogging-git-hooks/2018/10/08/blogging-git-hooks-added-hashbang.html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;+++ b/blogging-git-hook.sh
+#!/bin/bash
+previousVersion=
+git diff $previousVersion |grep ^+|more
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was automatically generated from a git commit&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Logan Streondj &lt;logan@liberit.ca&gt;</name></author><summary type="html">+++ b/blogging-git-hook.sh +#!/bin/bash +previousVersion= +git diff $previousVersion |grep ^+|more This post was automatically generated from a git commit</summary></entry></feed>